This XML file does not appear to have any style information associated with it. The document tree is shown below.
<rss xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:media="http://search.yahoo.com/mrss/" version="2.0">
<channel>
<title>E&T News</title>
<description>The latest news from E&T magazine</description>
<atom:link href="https://eandt.theiet.org/rss" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
<link>http://eandt.theiet.org</link>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Wimbledon’s technology grand slam: IBM, Watson and the high-tech bunker
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/wimbledon-s-technology-grand-slam-ibm-watson-and-the-high-tech-bunker/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3892/wimbledon-2017-ibm-bunker.jpg?center=0.69969040247678016,0.49292452830188677&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131435664980000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3892/wimbledon-2017-ibm-bunker.jpg?center=0.69969040247678016,0.49292452830188677&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131435664980000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>For two weeks every July, the eyes of the nation turn to a small patch of prime real estate in south-west London, focusing on the sport of tennis, which for the rest of the year most people only notice when Andy Murray wins a Grand Slam or when spats between players and former players, like John
]]>
<![CDATA[
McEnroe and Serena Williams, hit the headlines.</p> <p>Wimbledon is one of Britain’s oldest sporting treasures. As one of four global tennis Grand Slams, alongside the French, US and Australian Opens, it’s popular all over the world, with the tennis buffs, general sports fans and culture vultures. Lots of people visit the actual championships - around 494,000 last year, watching 674 matches, eating 86,000 ice creams and 28,000kg of strawberries and drinking 320,000 glasses of Pimms - but many more watch Wimbledon remotely.</p> <p>Traditional live television broadcasts are still popular, but according to the All England Lawn Tennis and Croquet Club (AELTC), Wimbledon’s hosts and organisers, increasing numbers of people are engaging with the Wimbledon Championships on their own terms in new ways.</p> <p>Back in 1868, when the AELTC was founded as a private members club for croquet players, there was a bit of primitive photography around, but no such thing as moving pictures. Back then, tennis was still a developing sport and wasn’t played at the club until 1875. The following year, Ferdinand Hunter and Vero Charles Driffield began their pioneering work on the light sensitivity of photographic emulsions which would lead to the development of film.</p> <p>These days, coverage of tennis at Wimbledon is much more sophisticated. Recent years have seen the introduction of live streaming from all courts, roving cameras and reporters travelling around the grounds and a social media splurge coordinated from a high-tech communications bunker, driven by Watson, the machine learning platform devised by IBM, the Championships’ technology partner.</p> <p>According to IBM, Watson can analyse data from around the courts and from social media much faster than human analysts: four hundred tweets a second last year, according to Sam Seddon, IBM’s client executive for Wimbledon.</p> <p>This year, as the AELTC prepares for its 150th anniversary in 2018, when it will take over from the BBC as host broadcaster, new technologies are being tried out. The AELTC says it wants to broaden and deepen the way people inside the venue and outside can engage with the tournament.</p> <p>A major tennis tournament is unique amongst sporting events in that many matches take place simultaneously, throughout the day. Wimbledon has eighteen playing courts and twenty two practice courts. Over a thousand players - singles, doubles, juniors and disabled, took part in the 2016 Championships.</p> <p>Traditionally, visitors would buy a ticket for a particular court and stay there, watching whoever was booked to play, stepping out for some refreshments if the game was a bit dull or one-sided.</p> <p>According to Alexandra Willis, the AELTC’s head of communications content and digital, many Wimbledon visitors are either newcomers and don’t know what to do or they are regulars with a regular routine.</p> <p>To help people find the resale ticket queue, the prawn sandwich bar or to generally just plan their day, IBM has devised an app that provides visitors with information about what is going on, where and when. ‘Ask Fred’ is named after the iconic former three-time Wimbledon men’s singles champion, Fred Perry. Until Andy Murray won the men’s singles in 2013, Perry - who won in the 1930s - was Britain’s only men’s singles champion since the First World War.</p> <p>The app is enabled by IBM Watson’s natural-language capabilities and is supported by three new Wi-Fi hotspots around the venue. It can respond to a user’s questions and, Willis says, gather together information about the sort of questions fans are asking, so organisers can meet fans’ needs next year and beyond. Either that or target them with marketing messages, depending on which way you look at it.</p> <p>Also new for this year, spectators can visit the practice courts and use the Wimbledon app to project an augmented reality overlay with stats about who is practicing with who. The AELTC and IBM are looking into ways of introducing this function for remote viewers over the coming years. In fact, most of the new technology being introduced at Wimbledon this year is aimed at the fans off-site.</p> <p>Last year, around one billion people in 200 countries tuned in to the Championships, but not all of them watched the tennis, live on television. The Wimbledon web site had 10.2 million unique visitors and the AELTC had 1.9 million requests for its live Wimbledon stream.</p> <p>Next year, however, when the AELTC becomes host broadcaster, there’ll be the small matter of a football World Cup to contend with. India, a lucrative market that the AELTC wants to break in to, will be playing England at cricket.</p> <p>“In many parts of the world, more people watch content through tablets than on TV,” says Mick Desmond, the AELTC’s commercial and media director. “Increasingly, people want to watch on their own terms, not make an appointment to view. If we want to stay in tune with the pace of change we have to look at new ways of reaching audiences, particularly younger audiences.”</p> <p>Willis adds that this year the AELTC will be launching Korean language content to go with the Chinese and Japanese they already provide. The new Indian content is in English and there’s also Spanish content, for the whole Spanish speaking world, aiming to capitalise on the popularity of the tennis event from last year’s Rio Olympics.</p> <p>The Wimbledon Channel, the official digital news channel of the tennis championships, will be live-streamed on social media, during the tournament and will also include news and behind-the-scenes footage from around the venue. “That could be in the queue, the hill, the kid zone, with kids visiting interview players. We won’t always be stuck in some studio,” Willis says.</p> <p>To the uniformed observer, a tennis match can easily appear to be nothing more than a flurry of arms, legs, rackets, balls and - according to critics of last year’s BBC coverage - a few too many close-up shots of women players’ underwear.</p> <p>Commentators, pundits and TV analysts do their best to highlight the game’s nuances, but viewed live, tennis is a fast-moving sport and there’s not always enough time to focus on the deeper aspects, when there’s a high-speed rally or a 140km/h serve to drool over.</p> <p>This, according to the AELTC and IBM, is where technology can play a significant part.</p> <p>This year, tournament organisers are introducing a new metric that they call competitive margin. This compares the players’ ratios of forced to unforced errors. From this, predictions can be made about how well-matched particular opponents are. There’s also a stats-based analysis of how well certain players tend to do in different situations, e.g. at break point down, during tie breaks or when they’ve just broken serve. The technology also points out what strategies each player might use in a given match and who is most likely to win.</p> <p>“Why does Nadal always deliver to Federer’s backhand on the first point of a pressure game?” Willis asks. “Why is a player winning and why is the other one losing and how might the losing player get that balance to shift or momentum to change?</p> <p>Willis explains that using millions of data points in the right way turns that data from mere statistics into insights that enable fans to get under the skin of a game.</p> <p>“It brings more meaning to content,” Desmond adds. “It’s not just passive watching and reading, but content which provides insights and can be shared with other fans.”</p> <p>There are other such technologies on show at this year’s Wimbledon for the first time. At the beginning of a match, fans can launch IBM Slam Tracker to check out what IBM calls “a players’ keys to the match”.</p> <p>Slam Tracker has been at SW17 for a while. It’s a cross-platform application that provides real-time scores, stats and insights for all matches in progress. This year, the technology will provide additional insights into areas such as how fast the game is moving, where players are serving and whether a player prefers to play from the baseline or the net.</p> <p>Real-time data will be integrated from multiple sources including courtside statisticians, chair umpires, radar guns, ball position, player location and even Twitter.</p> <p>Slam Tracker insights appear on Wimbledon.com. “Previously they were only live during a match,” Alexandra Willis says. “Now, there’s a preview state, so people can also look at specific pressure points that might occur during a match.”</p> <p>Sam Seddon adds that the idea behind this is to make people aware of where and when a particular match has a pressure point: “Then they can watch that game rather than another, which is love-all at the beginning of a set.”</p> <p>IBM techies will also be using Watson to generate video highlights of individual games. Willis says that, previously, one video editor - not necessarily someone with tennis knowledge - decided what the highlights package should contain, which was time-consuming.</p> <p>Watson’s artificial intelligence system picks the key moments of a match based on analysis of the crowd noise, players’ facial expressions and a knowledge of when the decisive moments such as set and break points took place. This, Sam Seddon says, reduces the time it takes to produce highlights and enables editorial teams to focus on writing news stories and articles.</p> <p>Seddon adds that the facial-recognition software also highlights players and celebrities around the venue when they first appear. This enables the Wimbledon photo-editing team to distribute the photos to different media channels even quicker.</p> <p>Sports fans, whatever the sport, like nothing more than to play pundit, sharing their expert views to friends and family and a wider audience, via social media. As if the armchair McEnroes and barstool Beckers needed encouraging, IBM has now started a discussion, based on masses of collected data and analytical insights inferred from the data, about who might be the greatest Wimbledon champion.</p> <p>IBM staff have programmed Watson with over 53 million data points captured from newspapers, blogs and books since 1990 to identify key tennis performance measures against a set of attributes required to make a great champion. Based on this, and discussions with expert analysts and former players, fans are invited to make their own deductions about who the greatest-ever champion might be.</p> <p>Key attributes might be passion, how a player performs under pressure, their stamina and the tactics they use, as well as their ability to produce a great serve and a great return. Seddon adds that this sort of analysis can produce ideas that human pundits alone, however astute and knowledgeable, might not necessarily see.</p> <p>For instance, Seddon explains, people have always thought that Rafa Nadal plays better at Wimbledon when the weather is hot, as in his native Spain, and that it’s Roger Federer, the ice-cool Swiss champion, who prefers the chillier weather. “When we ran this analysis through Watson, we found out, actually, the reverse is true,” Seddon says.</p> <p>He adds that when analysing the concept of passion, it was discovered that seven of the ten former champions who most often challenged authority were women. “Is the ability to successfully challenge authority a key component of what it takes to make a great women’s champion?” Seddon wonders. IBM will be putting out lots of these sorts of discussion points in order to get people off their armchairs and barstools and on to social media, engaging with Wimbledon’s digital content.</p> <p>Ahead of the 150th anniversary next year, the AELTC’s mission is to change people’s perception about the content they deliver and bring it into the 21st century. The fact that an organisation, criticised so often in the past for being archaic and elitist, is thinking and talking in terms of content instead of tennis in order to appeal to the masses is itself an indicator of how far things have come from the days when well-to-do gentlemen and ladies played croquet and a bit of tennis, on the lawns of their luxurious new private members’ club. </p> <p><a href="http://www.wimbledon.com/index.html">http://www.wimbledon.com/index.html</a></p> <p><a href="https://www.ibm.com/watson/">https://www.ibm.com/watson/</a></p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Crispin Andrews ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 3 Jul 2017 17:05:05 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ sport ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ supercomputer ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/wimbledon-s-technology-grand-slam-ibm-watson-and-the-high-tech-bunker/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Tesla’s Model 3 finally goes on sale, but new customers face a long wait
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/tesla-s-model-3-finally-goes-on-sale-but-new-customers-face-a-long-wait/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3896/2017-07-03t135433z_1321176320_rc181f4f6e70_rtrmadp_3_tesla-model-3.jpg?center=0.72982456140350882,0.568&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131435702360000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3896/2017-07-03t135433z_1321176320_rc181f4f6e70_rtrmadp_3_tesla-model-3.jpg?center=0.72982456140350882,0.568&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131435702360000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The five-seat electric car will be able to travel up to 215 kilometres on a single charge and will be sporty, accelerating from zero to 60mph in under six seconds.</p> <p>Customers have been feverishly awaiting the car due to its relatively low price compared to other Tesla models, costing as it will around $35,000 (£26,000).</p> <p>Company CEO Elon Musk had said production was on track to start in July, but Tesla often faces delays in getting vehicles to market.</p> <p>The California-based company aims to make 5,000 Model 3 sedans per week by the end of this year and 10,000 per week in 2018.</p> <p>Tesla has not said how many people have put down a $1,000 (£767) refundable deposit for the Model 3, but Musk said people who put down a deposit now will not get a car until the end of 2018, suggesting the pre-order number could be close to 500,000.</p> <p>The firm’s last new vehicle, <a href="/content/articles/2015/09/tesla-debuts-model-x-suv-with-delorean-style-gullwing-doors/" target="_blank">the Model X SUV </a>which features DeLorean-style gullwing doors and costs £130,000, was delayed by nearly 18 months. </p> <p>Musk said the Model 3 is much simpler to make, but the 14-year-old Tesla has no experience in producing and selling vehicles in high volumes.</p> <p>Tesla made just 84,000 cars last year. Bigger rivals like General Motors, Volkswagen and Toyota routinely sell around 10 million vehicles per year. Even if the Model 3 is delivered on time, servicing all those vehicles will still provide a challenge.</p> <p>Model S and Model X owners are already worried about having to share Tesla’s company-owned charging stations with an influx of new cars and while Tesla is promising to increase its network of stores and service centres by 30 per cent this year, it began 2017 with just 250 service centres worldwide. That leaves many potential owners miles from a service centre.</p> <p>Musk has said a new fleet of mobile service trucks will be deployed to help customers who are far from service centres.</p> <p>Tesla also plans to double its global high-speed charging points to 10,000 by the end of this year and increase them by another 50-100 per cent in 2018.</p> <p>Until recently, Tesla owned the market for fully-electric vehicles that can go 200 miles (324 kilometres) or more on a charge.</p> <p>However, this is changing. GM beat Tesla to the mass market <a href="/content/articles/2016/09/gm-releases-the-bolt-its-cheapest-electric-car-while-poland-aims-for-a-million-evs-on-its-roads-by-2025/" target="_blank">with the Chevrolet Bolt,</a> a 36,000 dollar (£27,000) car that goes 383 kilometres per charge. </p> <p>Audi plans to introduce an electric SUV with 486 kilometres of range next year and Ford aims to have one available by 2020. Volkswagen is already planning to have more than 30 electric vehicle models by 2025.</p> <p>Competitors like Mercedes and Volvo - not to mention tech companies like Google and Uber - can match Tesla’s efforts to develop self-driving vehicles. They also have deeper pockets. Thus far, Tesla has had only two profitable quarters in its seven years as a public company.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Jack Loughran ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 3 Jul 2017 16:49:51 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ tesla ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ electric vehicles ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ automotive ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ automotive engineering ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/tesla-s-model-3-finally-goes-on-sale-but-new-customers-face-a-long-wait/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Computer scientists gain insight into neural networks
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/computer-scientists-gain-insight-into-neural-networks/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3250/dreamstime_xxl_63218233.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131375084480000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3250/dreamstime_xxl_63218233.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131375084480000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>Neural networks learn to perform tasks by “training” using huge sets of data, in a similar way to how the human brain learns to detect patterns through experience. The networks are made up of a number of “nodes” (artificial neurons) which process information and pass it on to their neighbours through connections (artificial synapses), firing with varying strength.</p> <p>Despite our reliance on neural networks to take over important jobs in the future, such as controlling self-driving cars or to analyse video footage, we understand very little about how neural networks operate.</p> <p>In 2015, a team of computer vision researchers from MIT’s Computer Science and Artificial Intelligence Laboratory (CSAIL) outlined a basic technique looking into the workings of a neural network trained to identify scenes from images. Now, the CSAIL team is preparing to present a fully automated version of the same system: a neural network trained to perform more than 20 computer vision tasks, including colourising black and white images and recognising objects.</p> <p>The researchers adjusted the network in order to observe the strength with which individual nodes fire in response to training data. They were then able to identify the images that provokes the strongest response from each node.</p> <p>“We catalogued 1,100 visual concepts - things like the colour green, or a swirly texture, or wood material, or a human face, or a bicycle wheel, or a snowy mountaintop,” said Mr David Bau, a PhD student in the CSAIL. “We drew on several data sets that other people had developed and merged them into a broadly and densely labelled data set of visual concepts.”</p> <p>“It’s got many, many labels and for each label we know which pixels in which image correspond to that label.”</p> <p>By tracing responses between different “layers” of the neural network – responsible for different stages of processing data – the researchers were also able to tell which specific pixels corresponded to the most powerful responses. Low-level layers would respond to simple visual properties such as colour and texture, while high-level layers would fire in response to more complex properties.</p> <p>This allowed the CSAIL researchers to observe how networks devote different  numbers of nods to different tasks.</p> <p>Although every neural network is different, their work sheds light on how computer vision neural networks work beneath the surface, and could even be informative in the study of how the human brain is organised.</p> <p>For instance, their work has some parallels with a disputed hypothesis in neuroscience called the grandmother-neuron hypothesis, which suggests that some neurons respond only to specific visual stimuli (such as your grandmother’s face). The researchers found that – for an artificial neural network – they could identify individual nodes that were tuned to particular visual concepts.</p> <p>“To my eye, this is suggesting that neural networks are actually trying to approximate getting a grandmother neuron,” said Mr Bau. “They’re not trying to smear the idea of grandmother all over the place. They’re trying to assign it to a neuron. It’s this interesting hint of this structure that most people don’t believe is that simple.”</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Hilary Lamb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 3 Jul 2017 16:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ computing ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ computer vision ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ neural networks ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ machine learning ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ artificial intelligence ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/computer-scientists-gain-insight-into-neural-networks/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Raft of new Green Belt housing construction criticised for not being “affordable”
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/raft-of-new-green-belt-housing-construction-criticised-for-not-being-affordable/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3893/15797525-1-1.jpg?center=0.17869415807560138,0.49081364829396323&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131435670400000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3893/15797525-1-1.jpg?center=0.17869415807560138,0.49081364829396323&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131435670400000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>Some 425,000 homes are proposed for land released from the Green Belt under local and regional planning policies, analysis by the Campaign to Protect Rural England (CPRE) suggests, up 150,000 from its last study in March 2016.</p> <p>The assessment suggests that more than 70 per cent of those homes will not be expected to be “affordable” – with many representing low density development which feeds the high end of the market and does little to address the housing crisis.</p> <p>Less than one in six homes built on the Green Belt since 2009 outside the provisions of local plans was affordable, it found.</p> <p>Green Belt – the “countryside next door for 30 million people” which is designated to prevent urban sprawl – is under particular threat in the North West, West Midlands and South East, CPRE’s Green Belt Under Siege report revealed.</p> <p>It also suggests that the government’s “new homes bonus” initiative, which aims to relieve the housing crisis by incentivising local authorities to grant planning permission for new homes, will reward councils with £2.4bn for the 425,000 homes.</p> <p>The campaign group warned the initiative was rewarding development of Green Belt land which government policy aims to protect, without providing much needed affordable housing.</p> <p>Levels of planned affordable housing on Green Belt are particularly low in the North East and West Midlands, according to the report, which is based on local and city-regional planning policies and data from planning consultants Glenigan.</p> <p>The government should help councils build again and help fund genuinely affordable homes, including on small rural sites which can be well designed small scale development which provides affordable housing for local needs in the countryside, CPRE said.</p> <p>The campaign group also wants a focus on building on brownfield land which is suitable for redevelopment in towns and cities.</p> <p>Tom Fyans, director of campaigns and policy at CPRE, said: “Green Belt is being lost at an ever faster rate, yet the type of housing being built now or in the future will do very little to address the affordable housing crisis faced by many families and young people.</p> <p>“We must not be the generation that sells off our precious Green Belt in the mistaken belief it will help improve the affordability of housing.</p> <p>“The only ones set to benefit from future Green Belt development will be landowners and the big housebuilders, not communities in need of decent, affordable housing.”</p> <p>He said protecting the Green Belt was part of solving the housing crisis, encouraging the focus on the more-than one million homes that could be built on suitable brownfield sites.</p> <p>“The Green Belt makes our towns and cities better places to live. It provides quick access to the countryside.</p> <p>“The Government must do more to protect it,” he urged.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Jack Loughran ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 3 Jul 2017 15:53:09 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ construction industry ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/raft-of-new-green-belt-housing-construction-criticised-for-not-being-affordable/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Hinkley Point C nuclear plant build delayed as costs rise by a further &#163;1.5bn
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/hinkley-point-c-nuclear-plant-build-delayed-as-costs-rise-by-a-further-15bn/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/1702/hinkley.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131197077220000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/1702/hinkley.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131197077220000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The new estimations will not have any impact on the contract signed by EDF and the British government, the company has said.</p> <p>The French state-controlled utility raised its estimate for the project by £1.5bn above the original £18bn total. It also added that the risk of a deferral in the delivery (COD) of the project was estimated at 15 months for Unit 1.</p> <p>EDF energy director Vincent de Rivaz told journalists in a conference call that following discussions with the British government, the new cost estimates and delivery delay will have no impact on the Hinkley Point contract signed between the company, the British government and partners.</p> <p>The power station has had a tortured development process with the final approval being beset by delays and indecisiveness from both the government and the EDF board.</p> <p>It eventually <a href="/content/articles/2016/09/hinkley-point-contract-signed-in-private-ceremony/" target="_blank">received the final go ahead</a> in a private ceremony in London last September. </p> <p>The Prospect union has warned that jobs and investment could be lost unless the government urgently addresses the implications of Brexit for the civil nuclear industry.</p> <p>Prospect, which represents engineers and specialists, called for a new independent body to be established to develop the sector and help British firms competing for contracts abroad.</p> <p>Estimates suggest the global market for new nuclear projects and decommissioning over the next decade could be worth almost £1tr, with the market for new small modular reactors worth £250bn-£400bn, said the union.</p> <p>General secretary Mike Clancy said: “Britain is a world leader in nuclear engineering, research and decommissioning, yet we risk losing out as uncertainty and Brexit hit the industry.</p> <p>“We need clear leadership from government to get British nuclear back on track, helping to deliver new nuclear power generation, supporting innovation and creating more high-skilled jobs.</p> <p>“The Nuclear Safeguards bill announced in the Queen’s Speech fails to address the risk to jobs from leaving Euratom or concerns about new power stations at Hinkley Point C or Moorside in Cumbria.</p> <p>“That’s why we are calling for a new independent nuclear champion to advocate for the industry at home and abroad. In these uncertain times a properly resourced champion could put paid to uncertainty over nuclear, instead transforming the industry into an engine for jobs, growth and economic success.”</p> <p>A Business Department spokesman said: “In last week’s Queen’s Speech, this Government made clear our commitment to establishing a UK nuclear safeguards regime as we leave the European Union and Euratom.</p> <p>“There will be no immediate changes to the UK’s safeguards arrangements, the exact details of which will be subject to detailed consultation with the regulator, industry and international partners.”</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Jack Loughran ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 3 Jul 2017 13:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ hinkley point ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ nuclear ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ brexit ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/hinkley-point-c-nuclear-plant-build-delayed-as-costs-rise-by-a-further-15bn/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
AI could lead to “cliff-edge” scenario of mass unemployment, PWC warns
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/ai-could-lead-to-cliff-edge-scenario-of-mass-unemployment-pwc-warns/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3017/dreamstime_l_22720244.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131352609730000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3017/dreamstime_l_22720244.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131352609730000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The professional services firm said AI had the power to overhaul business models and could leave workers sidelined and companies struggling to adjust unless preparations are made now.</p> <p>It said firms and the state must double down on their efforts to improve the education system and help workers retrain to ensure AI delivers the much-heralded boost to the UK economy.</p> <p>Jon Andrews, PwC’s head of technology and investments, said: “There are different sectors that will be impacted in different ways.</p> <p>“The vast majority [of workers] will not see the change happening to them and they will have a very different job by 2030. But some of them you can see coming and you can actually predict the changes.</p> <p>“If you take the logistics world, there is going to be a period of time as we move towards autonomous vehicles where it will continue to be cheaper to have an old vehicle that is non-autonomous with a person driving it.</p> <p>“Then, all of sudden, that will flip and the business case will change and it will be worthwhile making the investment in autonomous vehicles. So we will see a cliff in terms of jobs there going more quickly.</p> <p>“We need to be prepared as a country on how we retrain people to think what other jobs those people can do ahead of that. That will be largely predictable because you will be able to predict and see that business case changing.”</p> <p>Experts believe the rise of AI poses a threat to workers across the professions, from staff in fast-food restaurants to journalists, accountants and doctors.</p> <p>Around 30 per cent of UK jobs are at high risk of being eradicated by AI by 2030, PwC has estimated.</p> <p>Billionaire Microsoft founder Bill Gates mooted the possibility of creating a robot tax in order to plug the hole in public finances left by the jobs destroyed by automation.</p> <p>However, the rise of AI - coined the fourth industrial revolution - will also create new roles for human beings and could drive up productivity and bolster economic growth.</p> <p>Jonathan Gillham, PwC’s director of economics, said: “It will lead to some sectors experiencing strong and rapid growth, but the job of the UK policy community is to help create the right labour force going forward to meet that.</p> <p>“We assume that the cost of those workers will rise because skills are going to be quite rare, they are going to be quite niche, but they do have to exist.</p> <p>“We need to upskill workers that are currently in the labour market and improve our education systems.”</p> <p>Last month, computer scientists at Rice University in Texas developed a method to <a href="/content/articles/2017/06/ai-learning-time-for-machines-slashed-by-95-per-cent-using-new-shortcut/" target="_blank">cut 95 per cent of computations </a>required for deep learning and massive neural networks. </p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ E&amp;T editorial staff ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 3 Jul 2017 13:00:53 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ artificial intelligence ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ jobs ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/ai-could-lead-to-cliff-edge-scenario-of-mass-unemployment-pwc-warns/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Scorpion-milking robot aims to end manual venom collection
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/scorpion-milking-robot-aims-to-end-manual-venom-collection/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3888/dreamstime_xl_911637.jpg?center=0.422680412371134,0.50393700787401574&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131435560370000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3888/dreamstime_xl_911637.jpg?center=0.422680412371134,0.50393700787401574&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131435560370000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>Scorpion venom is a complex substance, capable of producing a range of specialised effects in different animals. It contains proteins and other biologically active compounds, many of which are valuable in medical research and treatments. They are used in immunosuppressants, anti-malarial drugs an
]]>
<![CDATA[
d some cancer research.</p> <p><a href="http://www.cockeyed.com/science/gallon/liquid.html">One informal analysis</a> ranked scorpion venom as the most expensive liquid on earth, at nearly $39 million per gallon ($8.5 million per litre). While scorpion venom is highly sought after, the traditional methods for harvesting it can be life-threatening.</p> <p>Electrical stimulation involves dunking a live scorpion in a salty solution to improve electrical conduction and shocking the animal with a simple battery, before manually milking the scorpion by massaging its abdomen to release venom. These methods can be dangerous and unreliable.</p> <p>Safer alternatives – such as puncturing the scorpion’s venom gland or abdominal removal – tend to be harmful or lethal to the animal.</p> <p>“The extraction of scorpion venom is a very difficult task and usually takes at least two experimenters,” said Mouad Mkamel, who built the robot with a team of researchers from Ben M’sik Hassan II University in Morocco.</p> <p>“There are numerous risks including potentially deadly scorpion stings and electric shocks from the stimulators used to extract the venom.”</p> <p>The VES-4 device was created as a lightweight, portable tool for researchers in the lab and in the field needing to extract high-quality venom without harm to themselves or the animal.  According to the researches, it can be remotely operated by a single experimenter, while traditional methods normally require a team to handle the scorpion.</p> <p>The robot clamps the scorpion’s tail and stimulates the animal with electricity to release droplets of venom, which can be stored securely. It has been tested on various species of scorpion and can be programmed to adjust its settings for different species.</p> <p>“This robot makes venom recover fast and safe,” Mr Mkamel concludes.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Hilary Lamb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 3 Jul 2017 12:45:40 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ healthcare technologies ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ robots ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ animals ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/scorpion-milking-robot-aims-to-end-manual-venom-collection/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Chinese lunar mission rocket fails one hour after launch
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/chinese-lunar-mission-rocket-fails-one-hour-after-launch/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3887/long-march-rocket.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131435519870000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3887/long-march-rocket.jpg?crop=0,0.3276,0,0.17880624999999994&cropmode=percentage&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131435519870000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The Long March-5 Y2 rocket was launched from Wenchang Satellite Launch Center in Wanchang, in the island province of Hainan in the South China Sea. The rocket cleared the atmosphere, but then failed approximately one hour after take-off. The satellite eventually plunged into the Pacific Ocean.</p> <p>“An anomaly occurred during the flight of the rocket,” Xinhua news agency reported. “Further investigation will be carried out.”</p> <p>This is the second rocket launch failure in a fortnight for China: on June 19, a Long March-3 rocket attempting to deliver a broadcasting satellite into orbit failed to enter the correct orbit.</p> <p>The Long March-5 model is the second most powerful rocket in the world (after the American Delta IV Heavy) in terms of payload capacity. The failed rocket was carrying China’s heaviest satellite ever, the government reported. This was the Sijian-18, an experimental communications satellite.</p> <div class="responsive-media video"> <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/o2-_-GC9sM4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe> </div> <p>The heavy-lift rocket, generally considered very reliable, completed a successful launch from the same space centre in November 2016.</p> <p>Chinese President Xi Jinping has promised to accelerate China’s space programme, particularly for the sake of defence and national security. Beijing has described the programme as peaceful, intended to prevent hostile nations using their space assets for aggression.</p> <p>In 2003, China became the third country – after the US and Russia – to independently send humans into space, with the Shenzhou 5 mission.</p> <p>Ambitions for the Chinese space programme include a permanent space station by 2020, and manned lunar missions. The ongoing Chinese Lunar Exploration (Chang’e) Program comprises a series of unmanned lunar missions, using orbiters, landers, rovers and other spacecraft to study the moon. Leading figures in the Chang’e programme, including chief scientist Professor Ouyang Ziyuan, have advocated the exploitation of valuable lunar resources such as titanium and helium-3.</p> <p>The Chang’e 3 lunar orbiter, which carried the Yutu (“Jade Rabbit”) lunar rover, launched in 2013, and ran into some technical difficulties.</p> <p>Its successor, Chang’e 5, is scheduled for 2017. It will use a Long March-5 rocket to carry cameras, analytical instruments and a robotic drilling rig to the moon, and will attempt to collect and return lunar samples to Earth. It is not known how this ambitious mission may be affected by the failure of the launch.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Hilary Lamb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 3 Jul 2017 11:41:26 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ space research ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ china ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ rockets ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ satellites ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/chinese-lunar-mission-rocket-fails-one-hour-after-launch/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[ View from Washington: The Circle goes nowhere ]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/view-from-washington-the-circle-goes-nowhere/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3890/paul-03-07-17.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131435571350000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3890/paul-03-07-17.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131435571350000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>I saw <em>The Circle</em>, Hollywood’s latest paranoid cyber thriller, as a rainy-afternoon escape into a cinema. You have it easier. In the UK, the film has gone straight to Netflix after an unsuccessful US theatrical run and damning reviews.</p> <p>You may be expecting me to now offer a more positive reappraisal. But no, this is a bad movie. Its usefulness is rather as a cautionary tale showing why (with rare exceptions like Charlie Brooker’s <em>Black Mirror</em>) fiction struggles with technological satire.</p> <p>You can see how the project attracted serious talent. The cast includes Emma Watson, Tom Hanks, Patton Oswalt, John Boyega, Karen Gillan and the late Bill Paxton. Director James Ponsoldt was hot off an excellent biopic about novelist David Foster Wallace, <em>The End of the Tour</em>. The source was a novel by the usually reliable Dave Eggers (<em>A Heartbreaking Work of Staggering Genius</em>) who also co-wrote the screenplay.</p> <p>All no doubt saw <em>The Circle</em> as a chance to address A REALLY BIG ISSUE [sic]. Yes, the Internet does seem to be threatening our privacy and our freedoms.</p> <p>The film locates its tale well. The Circle is a blend of Facebook, Google and Apple. It is a social media corporation that stretches far into its users’ lives, which also fosters a dangerously inward-looking cult of belonging in the employees. The creepy exclusivity of today’s tech giants is causing serious tensions in Silicon Valley.</p> <p>The first problem, though, is that the film makes characters behave in unbelievably silly ways. For example, it depicts a corporate culture where employees are expected to be at least graduates, even to work the phones in customer support. They are also shown to undergo psychological profiling before being hired. So, when one reacts to stress by stealing a kayak for an ill-fated midnight joypaddle, the result is – erm – promotion.</p> <p>Then there are the bad guys: Hanks as The Circle’s charismatic TED talk-giving leader and Oswalt as his corporate enforcer. Casting two of cinema’s most likeable actors so hard against type was full of interesting possibilities, but they are never properly explored.</p> <p>The two are instead branded with their own type of stoopid. We learn that they have given The Circle’s disenchanted third founder and main code-slinger (Boyega) retirement in the form of access to the company’s entire campus, including its most secure servers. You know, the ones that can give access to all their truly dodgy secrets.</p> <p>A good friend of mine who works as a Valley venture capitalist asserts that the success of any technology company comes down to “at least 50 per cent SDL”, with management, engineering, marketing and everything else squabbling over the remainder. When asked what “SDL” is, he’s only too happy to explain: “sheer dumb luck”.</p> <p>Precious few Valley titans are as smart as they think they are, yet <em>The Circle</em> piles up incongruities faster than Amazon stocks its warehouse shelves. Barely five minutes go by without a character sparking another, “Sorry, you what?” moment.</p> <p>I haven’t even got in to the script’s attempts to mint its own ‘newspeak’, such as “Secrets are lies”, “Sharing is caring”, and “Knowing is good, but knowing everything is better.” If you’re going to invoke Orwell so blatantly, you had better be absolutely on your game.</p> <p>Strangely though, the film could have got away with much of that, if it had some teeth or some wit. Satire based on smart people doing daft stuff can work if events are felt to be building up a crescendo of catastrophe<em>.</em></p> <p>Only one moment in <em>The Circle</em> hints at such appropriately grotesque possibilities. Two co-workers offer Watson’s newbie a Stepfordian description of the ‘voluntary’ in-house social and office-hours policy. As things progress, the worst consequence of that turns out to be - I kid you not - a bad case of red-eye that sparks a boardroom hissy fit.</p> <p>This brings us to <em>The Circle’s</em> second major failing. It refuses to deploy the greatest weapon in the satirist’s arsenal, the <em>reductio ad absurdum</em>. It is absurd alright, but it refuses to expose the absurdities and dangers of digital intrusion. Rather, it seems entranced by the world it would satirise.</p> <p>Hanks’ TED-like pontifications to his workforce are so lovingly filmed, they should get Ponsoldt a gig directing the stream of Apple’s next product launch. Meanwhile, Boyega’s ‘honest’ founder is left skulking in the background, given voice only for the sake of plot exposition rather than the articulation of a theme. Then again, he fares better than the film’s other voice of conscience, Watson’s former boyfriend. He is given the off-grid job of fashioning chandeliers from deer antlers. Like I said, “Sorry, you what?”</p> <p>It is in this last regard that <em>The Circle</em> is a cautionary tale, mainly for those who would dramatically explore the potential impact of the digital world. Film and TV are themselves now highly digitised processes. Directors and writers too often fall in love with sleek machines, cool graphics and the blandishments of technological determinism. The best, like Brooker, look beyond those and nurture some bile for their observations.</p> <p>That <em>The Circle </em>gets a kicking for failing to vent anything of note is largely down to its pedigree. More mediocre equivalents have slumped in the same way, but the talents involved did not have as far to fall.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Paul Dempsey ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 3 Jul 2017 10:07:47 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ view from washington ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ privacy ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ entertainment ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/view-from-washington-the-circle-goes-nowhere/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[ View from India: ITC Infotech unveils ‘iTech 2017’ ]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/view-from-india-itc-infotech-unveils-itech-2017/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3889/kavitha-03-07-17.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131435564660000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3889/kavitha-03-07-17.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131435564660000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The event will run two parallel tracks, which include a Codeathon and startup ‘Showcase’ segment. The Codeathon encourages participants to create code components for complex business applications. Brownie points include cash prizes worth Rs 6 Lakh, along with on-spot internship and job opportunities. The winning startup will get a grant of Rs 5 lakh for a paid proof of concept (POC) and an opportunity to work with the company to accelerate technology innovation.</p> <p>Through this new dimension, startups can explore newer technologies and tweak them for consumers. This endeavour is in sync with ITC Infotech’s vision of setting up ‘Innoruption Labs’, the concept of ‘innoruption’ being to combine the innovation and disruption. “At the Innoruption Labs, we work on Horizon 2 and Horizon 3 technologies. New technologies that are not yet fully mainstream will be leveraged to solve real-life problems,” said Mahesh Prabhu, VP and Global Head of Innovation, ITC Infotech.</p> <p>This will include cognitive computing, image analysis, chat bots, augmented reality (AR) and virtual reality (VR), among others. The Innoruption Labs has already made a move in this direction using many of these technologies. For instance, the Labs team has worked closely with a piping company to create a predictive model to identify the source and extent of leakage in water pipes. “A proof of concept has been used by an airline company to guide passengers through a crowded airport. That’s because the aircraft incurred huge costs due to delayed take-off,” highlighted Prabhu.</p> <p>Principles of AR/VR can be applied to remove the components of elevators. Newer technologies can be applied for creating cashless vending machines. Out-of-the box thinking will help in coupon redemption happen through sound technology. Mobile apps can be used in the retail industry, where the app will navigate shoppers towards the product.</p> <p>At the Innoruption Labs, a 23-member R&amp;D team has built prototypes to execute many such concepts, besides nurturing start ups that specialise in digital marketing campaigns, virtual gamification and non-intrusive advertising, among others. Already six startups have been nurtured over the last two years.</p> <p>One expects a new leash of ideas at iTech 2017. “We have set the bar high this year as the Codeathon gives participants an opportunity to complete projects that revolve round discreet problems. Many of these projects can be converted into business services,” Ms Sushma Rajagopalan, MD &amp; CEO, ITC Infotech explained, adding, “The floor is open for participants to build social chat application software and create mobile blogs. Even jigsaw puzzles can be oriented to educate students, besides being an entertaining session.”</p> <p>In the Codeathon segment, 40 teams will be shortlisted from the entries received and will face-off in a race against time to create code components for complex business applications. Participants can present their ideas across challenge areas provided by ITC Infotech. The event is free and open to all students, professionals, developers and early-stage technology startups.</p> <p>“iTech is where young technology disruptors and innovators from across India come together to celebrate all things ‘new’ in technology. Technocrats and business leaders from across our global client base will be joining us for these two days to understand how they can unlock the untapped opportunity within their organizations through the latest digital technologies,” explained Ms Rajagopalan.</p> <p>iTech 2017 is envisioned to bring together some of the sharpest technology minds to compete, create and code, while interacting closely with the vibrant ecosystem of entrepreneurs and business leaders of the future.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Kavitha Srinivasa ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Mon, 3 Jul 2017 10:05:55 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ view from india ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/view-from-india-itc-infotech-unveils-itech-2017/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Google fine, Gaza island, Boaty McBoatface and more: pick of the week’s tech news
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/best-of-the-weeks-news-300617/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3837/google-logo-eu.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131430352870000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3837/google-logo-eu.jpg?crop=0,0.33435982799278674,0,0.1750034678873631&cropmode=percentage&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131430352870000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<h3>Jack Loughran, news reporter</h3> <h3><a href="/content/articles/2017/06/google-s-24bn-fine-opens-the-door-to-legal-action-from-rivals-and-an-eu-clampdown/" target="_blank">Google’s €2.4bn fine opens the door to legal action from rivals and an EU clampdown</a></h3> <p>Google’s hefty €2.4
]]>
<![CDATA[
bn fine was criticised in some quarters as stifling innovation, but really it’s Google itself that is doing the stifling. The EU has begun treating the search giant like a monopoly company; wholly appropriate when considering that in Europe at least it’s where 95 per cent of all internet searches take place. While the US has traditionally favoured business interests over all else, an ethos that will only ramp up under Donald Trump, the EU has recognised that Google’s business practices are dangerous, and ultimately bad for consumers.</p> <p>How can the argument be made that the EU is stifling innovation when Google’s rivals have such a small user base that any new or original search feature from them will be largely ignored by the vast majority of internet users and probably copied by Google in the long run anyway? The Big Three - Facebook, Google and Amazon - already have a dangerously high level of control over the internet and breaking their stranglehold is almost impossible because they have all the users. Their huge user bases bring both money and vast treasure troves of data to improve their services beyond the capabilities of anyone else who is trying to compete.</p> <p>To make a real-world comparison, if Amazon’s online retail presence was replicated on an average high street, nearly 50 per cent of the shops would be bearing its logo. With competition being the supposed driver of both innovation and lower prices for the consumer, huge dominance in the virtual space will only be a bad thing in the long run. Facebook and Google have the ability to determine all of the information that the average Joe has access to, giving them immense power. With this power they can swing elections and alter the prevailing opinions on virtually any issue they want. Sure maybe there isn’t much evidence that they are actively abusing this power yet, but the internet is still in its relative infancy, these companies are barely 20 years old and yet their potential significance in the geo-political mix is arguably larger than that of any country.</p> <p>The EU is right to start the clampdown now, keep Google in check, scrutinise its every action carefully and do as much as it can to prevent it from becoming the internet dictator it so clearly wants to be.</p> <h3>Josh Loeb, associate editor</h3> <h3><a href="/content/articles/2017/06/gaza-strip-artificial-island-to-feature-airport-seaport-desalination-plant-and-electricity-terminals/" target="_blank">Gaza Strip artificial island to feature airport, seaport, electricity plant</a></h3> <p>The word ‘intractable’ is often used to describe the Israeli-Palestinian conflict and discussion of it tends to become bogged down in a history which can seem impenetrable to the uninitiated. Do you want to go back 50 years to the Six Day War and the start of Israel’s occupation of the West Bank, 70 years to the establishment of the Jewish State and the Palestinian ‘Naqbah’ or two thousand years to the Romans’ destruction of the Temple in Jerusalem?.</p> <p>One interesting question is whether technological advances could ever banish, or at least neutralise, some of this deadly historical baggage. Given the non-existence of the peace process at present, don’t hold your breath, but as someone who takes an interest in events in this part of the world, I felt heartened to read about Israel’s plans for an artificial island port to serve the Palestinian Gaza Strip. Doubtless there are ifs and buts about the scheme, but at the most basic level it seems like a bright idea. The offshore geography and ease with which the island could be policed would help allay Israeli fears about security threats emanating from the Hamas-controlled enclave. At the same time, the proposed airport, logistics facility and power plant to be built on the man-made outpost would solve some of the dire problems (some of which Israel bears responsibility for) afflicting the Strip.</p> <p>As should be obvious to anyone with even a cursory knowledge of the Israeli-Palestinian conflict, it is basically all about territory. Land, in other words. Bear in mind that this land is very small, and, for various reasons, both peoples want all, or most, or many of the same bits, of it. As a result of this disagreement over who should have what, large numbers of people have died in a vicious cycle of raw emotion and violence. Could technology help transcend that by enabling more land to be built? What if cities could be extended miles up into the sky or onto the sea itself? With the right shift in attitudes, could such an extension of the land ever help to bring about peace? Or would human emotions overwhelm that?</p> <h3>Dickon Ross, editor in chief</h3> <h3><a href="/content/articles/2017/06/engineering-ceos-commit-to-tackling-gender-crisis/" target="_blank">Engineering CEOs commit to tackling gender crisis</a></h3> <p>International Women in Engineering Day, held a week ago today, has really taken off. Although it didn’t show up in all measures, the #INWED17 hashtag trended on Twitter - top in London for some of the day and up to fourth in the UK. Industry bosses called for ‘action from the top’ to address the problem at the IET’s #9PerCentIsNotEnough conference in Birmingham on Friday, which I attended. The conference heard that the percentage of women in engineering has crept up just a couple of percentage points in the last 20 or 30 years. Our last issue focusing on the lack of women in engineering attracted an unprecedented response from readers, which we’ll sum up in our next issue. It’s becoming clear to me that while some organisations are doing more to address the problem, many in the engineering profession still don’t get it. Treating everyone the same, as some throw out as a solution as if it speaks for itself, means continuing discrimination and inequalities for women and fails to raise diversity in other ways too. The theme of this year’s INWED was ‘Men as Allies’ and I would urge more men to take part next year and go and listen to the experiences of their female colleagues. If they listen with an open mind they might be surprised by what they hear. Our poll on the best ad campaign concept to attract more women into engineering has also had an unprecedented response for an E&amp;T poll. We’re closing the poll on Sunday evening so you have just a few more days to vote if you haven’t already. See the ideas and vote at <a href="/content/articles/2017/06/rebranding-engineering-for-women-choose-your-favourite-advert/" target="_blank">https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/rebranding-engineering-for-women-choose-your-favourite-advert/</a>.</p> <h3>Jade Fell, supplements editor</h3> <h3><a href="/content/articles/2017/06/boaty-mcboatface-completes-first-mission/" target="_blank">Boaty McBoatface completes first mission</a></h3> <p>Boaty McBoatface is my favourite autonomous research submarine of all time, and not just because he has quite literally the best name in the history of all named things. Also known by the much less exotic ‘Autsub Long Range’, Boaty has a total range of 6000km, an endurance of six months and a depth rating of 6000m, making him the most advanced of all the BAS autonomous research vessels. This handsome little chap can travel more than ten times the distance of the boring Autosub3 and the Autosub6000, and can be deployed for over a hundred times the duration. With stats like this, it’s a dead cert that this is the first of many successful missions for Boaty.</p> <h3>Vitali Vitaliev, features editor</h3> <h3><a href="/content/articles/2017/06/cyber-assault-wreaks-havoc-on-ukraine-and-infects-major-global-companies-it-systems/" target="_blank">Cyber assault wreaks havoc on Ukraine and infects major global companies' IT systems</a></h3> <p>I was relieved to see this news story on Wednesday, for on Tuesday night they announced on the news that the cyber attack originated from Ukraine and could even be government inspired. I was very surprised: with all its new democratic freedoms and institutions, my native country was an unlikely aggressor – cyber or other. On the contrary, it is at the moment trying to fight an aggression against itself by Russia, the country that has become notorious of late for its imperialist policy (annexing the Crimea, for example), both on the ground and online. From the E&amp;T report, it transpires that Ukraine, rather than being an organiser of the vicious cyber attack that has so far affected a number of countries including Britain, was in fact one of its victims. So where should UK Defence Secretary Michael Fallon “send troops or authorise air strikes in retaliation for any future cyber attack”? We can only guess. Remembering that the latest cyber threats originated mostly from three countries - North Korea, China and Russia – I don’t see Mr Fallon sending troops or authorising air strikes again any of them in the near future.</p> <h3><a href="/content/articles/2017/06/spider-like-graphene-robots-crawl-with-no-external-power-source/" target="_blank">Spider-like graphene ‘robots’ crawl with no external power source</a></h3> <p>What is it about snakes and spiders that fascinates the creators of robots so much? This time last week I highlighted a story about the plans to use <a href="/content/articles/2017/06/best-of-the-weeks-news-230617/" target="_blank">snake-like robots on the International Space Station</a>. Do creepy crawlies carry some kind of perverse attraction for engineers and scientists? I bet none of the people behind those two robot types have lived in Australia, where both snakes and spiders are among the world’s most poisonous and are unlikely to inspire many artists or designers, let alone scientists and engineers. With all the negative publicity AI creations are getting these days (robots are going to take over the world; our jobs, our houses etc), why can’t they think of flower or bird-shaped robots instead?</p> <h3>Tim Fryer, Technology Editor</h3> <h3><a href="/content/articles/2017/06/gaza-strip-artificial-island-to-feature-airport-seaport-desalination-plant-and-electricity-terminals/" target="_blank">Gaza strip artificial island to feature airport, seaport, electricity plant</a></h3> <p>I saw this story and my first instinct was “it ain’t happening”. When I read it through fully my thought had progressed to “it definitely ain’t happening”. It would be a great project and the technology behind its construction and infrastructure would be considerable. However, if Israel was serious about giving the Gaza strip better access to the outside world then should it not just allow Gaza to open a land-based port, rather than build an offshore one connected by a single, vulnerable and controllable bridge? Conceptually the problem in the UK is we still can’t fully accept a completely polarised argument, despite the Irish troubles and the recent rise of Middle East based extremism – it is equally unfair to connect and blame any particular region as it is with any religion, but we do have to have some label. I have heard so many debates with both Palestinians and Israelis instinctively adopting an attitude of arguing black was white rather than concede any quarter to the enemy. Anything that could have a genuine hope of resolution or co-operation is no more than empty words aimed at appeasing the international audience. And that is where I think this scheme fits. I hope my perceptions are out of date and that I am completely wrong – I really would be delighted to see the evidence of my error being built in harmonious waters off Gaza.</p> <h3>Jonathan Wilson, online managing editor</h3> <h3><a href="/content/articles/2017/06/security-fears-loom-over-police-force-s-continuing-use-of-windows-xp/" target="_blank">Security fears loom over police force’s continuing use of Windows XP</a></h3> <p>The fact that anyone is still using Windows XP in 2017 is baffling enough, given that the developer Microsoft abandoned it in 2014 and made it very clear that there would be no more security patches. How the Met comes to still be using XP on 18,000 PCs at a time when a cyber-security attack is one of the most prevalent crimes threatening us all is even more perplexing. Why wouldn’t you update your software to the latest version - or at least move on from a version known to have been deprecated by its manufacturer? It’s like the police coming round to your house after a burglary and telling you to change the locks, only you then decide to leave the front door wide open for the rest of your born days. I’m sure the lack of computer updates is absolutely nothing to do with budget cuts and a government crackdown on public spending as part of its austerity measures (which naturally don’t include rejecting 10 per cent annual pay increases for our hard-working MPs). At least the Met can comfort itself with the thought that it’s not the only frontline national defence organisation still running the Stone Age ‘Swiss cheese’ operating system. Apparently, HMS Queen Elizabeth, the Royal Navy's new £3.5bn aircraft carrier, is also running Windows XP in her control room. “Hey, who fired those torpedoes?”</p> <h3><a href="/content/articles/2017/06/china-and-canada-governments-commit-to-ending-economic-cyber-espionage/" target="_blank">China and Canada governments commit to ending economic cyber espionage</a></h3> <p>Well, this is nice. The governments of China and Canada have signed a deal promising not to target each other with particular types of cyber attacks. Not all cyber attacks, just some of them. The two countries have vowed to no longer commit state-sponsored cyber attacks aimed at extracting trade secrets or confidential business information, although they will still engage in a bit of state-sponsored cyber espionage now and again, presumably just for the LOLs. I can’t help feeling this is a good wheeze dreamed up by the Canadians and the Chinese in order to have a laugh at America’s expense. Canada is widely perceived as being a lot like America, only better, cleaner, classier and smarter and I’m sure the Chinese are well aware that befriending America’s more refined neighbour in this way will get right up Trump’s nose. Next week: North Korea buddies up with Mexico, signing an agreement not to bomb each other with nuclear weapons.</p> <h3>Lorna Sharpe, sub-editor</h3> <h3><a href="/content/articles/2017/06/boaty-mcboatface-completes-first-mission/" target="_blank">Boaty McBoatface completes first mission</a></h3> <p>"A rose by any other name would smell as sweet,” said Shakespeare. That’s true, but names help us create associations and connections in our minds. I don’t really have the skills for a successful career in marketing, but I doubt if I would have looked at a story headlined ‘Autosub LR completes first mission’.</p> <h3><a href="/content/articles/2017/06/lidar-system-able-to-penetrate-foliage-and-map-obscured-environments/" target="_blank">Lidar system able to penetrate foliage and map obscured environments</a></h3> <p>This really is a technically interesting development, but again - as with Boaty McBoatface - it’s the associations that caught my attention. Partly the word ‘lidar’, because I’ve written about this myself in the past, and partly the accompanying picture. The pink and purple flowers are of a plant that has been happily self-seeding in my garden since the 1980s, but it was only a couple of months ago that I posted a photograph on Facebook asking if anyone knew what it was called, so now I know, thanks to a former IET colleague, that it’s aquilegia. And while I’m musing about connections, you might like to know that the phrase ‘only connect’ appears at the start of EM Forster’s novel ‘Howard’s End’, which was based on his childhood home of Rooks Nest House here in Stevenage. One thing leads to another.</p> <h3>Dominic Lenton, managing editor</h3> <h3><a href="/content/articles/2017/06/self-driving-vehicle-brings-groceries-to-scores-of-customers-as-part-of-8m-scheme/" target="_blank">Self-driving vehicle brings groceries to scores of customers as part of £8m scheme</a></h3> <p>Unfortunate that Ocado is the delivery company involved in this trial of using driverless delivery ‘pods’ because it gives me an opportunity to gripe a little. We’ve been using them for our family shopping a couple of times a week in recent months and found online ordering with an hour-long arrival slot a great alternative to slogging around the supermarket – as long as things go right. A couple of weeks ago, with a busy weekend ahead we got an hour’s notice that due to some unspecified ‘operational reasons’ the load of food we’d been expecting on a Thursday evening wouldn’t be there after all. We could arrange an alternative delivery, but who wants to take a chance on that failing as well? An unexpected trip to the shops Friday evening trying to remember what we’d been expecting wasn’t the best end to the week and will be a persistent memory every time we think about using Ocado in the future. You can’t help suspecting that robot deliveries are at risk from the same effect – they’ll be an entertaining novelty and welcome convenience until the first time they drop shopping off at the wrong address or get lost and will then be forever tainted by the idea that a human would never have made the same mistake. There’s one potential benefit to other road users though. Supermarket delivery vans are always in such a big hurry, presumably to hit tight deadlines, that they can be a menace. Self-driving versions will presumably be the best behaved traffic around, obeying every rule of the road as if they were taking their driving test. Can’t help wondering where they’ll park up in the situations where drivers currently just pull up onto the pavement at the moment, oblivious to the inconvenience they’re causing everyone else.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ E&amp;T editorial staff ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 16:27:48 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ best of the week ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/best-of-the-weeks-news-300617/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Acoustic properties of prehistoric caves examined for link with ancient paintings
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/acoustic-properties-of-prehistoric-caves-examined-for-link-with-ancient-paintings/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3886/cave-paintings.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131433098870000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3886/cave-paintings.jpg?crop=0,0.29721666666666663,0,0.21106458333333339&cropmode=percentage&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131433098870000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The exact purpose of cave paintings, which date back as far as 40,000 years, is unknown. Many scholars suggest that they could form part of early religious rituals or serve a decorative purpose in spaces for hunting groups to bond.</p> <p>One theory about the reasoning behind prehistoric cave pai
]]>
<![CDATA[
ntings proposes that the sites for painting were picked due to the good acoustic properties of the caves. If this were true, it could suggest that music played an important role in cave rituals tens of thousands of years ago.</p> <p>The academics who originally proposed this theory found that there was a correlation between “points of resonance” in three caves in France and the positions of Palaeolithic cave paintings.</p> <p>“Many structures throughout history featured reverberant spaces because reverberant sound can be awe-inspiring,” said David Lubman, an independent researcher in acoustics and a fellow of the Acoustical Society of America. “With that said, there is currently not enough evidence to suggest that these Paleolithic artists deliberately chose reverberant spaces for their paintings.”</p> <p>According to Mr Lubman, paintings are often found on non-porous stone, in spaces that have excellent acoustic properties. Whether this was a deliberate choice influenced by the acoustic properties of the caves, or whether paintings on porous stone have simply been lost over time, remains unknown.</p> <p>In order to help decide whether there is a strong causative link between reverberant spaces and cave paintings, Mr Lubman is proposing a more systematic and detailed acoustic study of the caves with remaining paintings.</p> <p>“If a significant degree of correlation between the location of the reverberant spaces and the presence of paintings were to be found, this alone would be an important discovery and opens up the possibility for new explanations,” said Mr Lubman. “It could, for example, be entirely possible that Palaeolithic cave artists initially chose spaces with non-porous stone because they were good canvasses for paintings and then subsequently discovered that they were also great locations to generate reverberant sound.”</p> <p>“The benefits of acoustical scientists and archaeologists collaborating on such studies are clear. Together, we can work towards developing a deeper understanding of our past.”</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Hilary Lamb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 16:26:13 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ engineering and technology in society ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ history ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/acoustic-properties-of-prehistoric-caves-examined-for-link-with-ancient-paintings/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
China tightens censorship rules to ensure the internet only propagates “core socialist values”
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/china-tightens-censorship-rules-to-ensure-the-internet-only-propagates-core-socialist-values/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3883/dreamstime_xl_66361008.jpg?center=0.34351145038167941,0.4941860465116279&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131433083780000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3883/dreamstime_xl_66361008.jpg?center=0.34351145038167941,0.4941860465116279&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131433083780000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>At least three “auditors” will have to check all movies, dramas, documentaries and animations posted online to ensure they adhere to “core socialist values”, the industry body the China Netcasting Services Association (CNSA) said.</p> <p>The rules, which build upon guidelines released in 2012, come as authorities are cracking down on online content such as literature, livestreaming, news and social media - a broad campaign aimed at controlling social discourse online.</p> <p>Weibo Corp, the operator of China’s top microblogging site, said this week it would block unapproved video content and work more closely with state media to promote “mainstream” ideas and shut down accounts that unsettle the government’s top brass following a sharp rebuke from regulators. <a href="/content/articles/2017/06/weibo-capitulates-amid-chinese-government-s-censorship-crackdown/">https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/weibo-capitulates-amid-chinese-government-s-censorship-crackdown/</a></p> <p>Authorities also ordered internet companies this month to close 60 celebrity gossip social media accounts to help “actively propagate core socialist values” and prop up “mainstream public opinion”.</p> <p>Under the new guidance, which comes into immediate effect, censors should check that content adheres to proper Chinese values and strive to tell Chinese stories to help “realise the China dream of a great rejuvenation of the Chinese nation.”</p> <p>Content should “sing the motherland, eulogize heroes, celebrate our times in song, and lead the people to hold the correct historical, ethnic, national and cultural view”.</p> <p>Programmes that undermined a respectful national image, ridiculed leaders, promoted negative or decadent views of life and showed the “dark side” of society would be edited, or in severe cases stopped.</p> <p>President Xi Jinping has overseen measures to clamp down on independent online media, while reasserting the ruling Communist Party’s role in limiting and guiding online discussion.</p> <p>The Cyberspace Administration of China in May released regulations for online news portals and network providers, which extended restrictions on content and required all services to be managed by party-sanctioned editorial staff.</p> <p>The new rules also laid out a range of issues that did not meet with approval, including violence, drug addiction, extramarital affairs and religious cults.</p> <p>Also on the list was homosexuality, underlining the conservative official view on same-sex relations.</p> <p>China <a href="/content/articles/2017/06/weibo-china-s-twitter-blocks-picture-and-video-uploads-by-users-on-tiananmen-anniversary/" target="_blank">blocked Weibo users from posting</a> pictures or video on their feeds earlier this month on the 28th anniversary of the bloody Tiananmen Square crackdown. </p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Jack Loughran ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 16:02:42 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ internet ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ china ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/07/china-tightens-censorship-rules-to-ensure-the-internet-only-propagates-core-socialist-values/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[ Raspberry Pi wins prestigious engineering prize ]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/raspberry-pi-wins-prestigious-macrobert-award-engineering-prize/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3882/raspberry-pi.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131433071570000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3882/raspberry-pi.jpg?crop=0,0.27681944444444445,0,0.23146180555555559&cropmode=percentage&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131433071570000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The Raspberry Pi was originally conceived at the University of Cambridge as a way to boost computer science applications, following a decline in applications early in the millennium.</p> <p>The affordable, versatile microcomputer can be used as the “brain” of lab experiments, robots and original smart home applications. The standard Raspberry Pi costs just £28, while the Raspberry Pi Zero, a stripped-down version, costs £5.</p> <p>The Raspberry Pi has video and audio capabilities with a range of inputs and outputs, including USB and HDMI. It owes its versatility to its multi-layered design, which allows components to be decoupled.</p> <div class="responsive-media video"> <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/YPDehg1pL9A" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe> </div> <p>So far, 14 million Raspberry Pi microcomputers have been sold, making it the best-selling British computer of all time. Although half of these are used in industry, the device has proved most influential in education.</p> <p>“Raspberry Pi’s original educational goal has actually resulted in a computer control system that can influence many different industries,” said Dr Dame Due Ion, who chaired the judging panel. “Raspberry Pi has also inspired multiple generations to get into coding: children are learning about coding for the first time, often alongside their parents and grandparents. Communities in the developing world are being empowered by the Raspberry Pi and its modern day computing-on-a-budget.”</p> <p>The MacRobert Award is run by the Royal Academy of Engineering, which has, in previous years, awarded the prize to the engineers behind the CT scanner, the catalytic convertor and light-emitting polymers.</p> <p>Other finalists were Darktrace, a machine learning company for cyber defences, and Vision RT, which develops technologies for radiotherapies. A judging panel composed of Fellows of the Academy selected the Raspberry Pi as the winning innovation, and HRH The Duke of Kent presented the engineers with their prize at the Academy Awards Dinner in London.</p> <p>The Cambridge-based team received a gold medal and a £50,000 prize.</p> <p>“What sets Raspberry Pi apart is the sheer quality of the innovation, which has allowed the computer to be used far beyond its original purpose,” said Dr Ion. “By blending old and new technology with innovative systems engineering and circuit board design, the team has created a computer that is cheap, robust, small and flexible.”</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Hilary Lamb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 15:40:37 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ computer applications ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ computer hardware ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ education ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/raspberry-pi-wins-prestigious-macrobert-award-engineering-prize/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Online fraud needs higher police priority, watchdog declares
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/online-fraud-threat-must-rise-up-priorities-list-watchdog-declares/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3881/guy-in-hoodie-at-laptop.jpg?center=0.70538243626062325,0.54427645788336931&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131433022870000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3881/guy-in-hoodie-at-laptop.jpg?center=0.70538243626062325,0.54427645788336931&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131433022870000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The UK's National Audit Office (NAO) today said the overall cost of all forms of fraud was £10bn to individuals and £144bn to the private sector as a whole in the last calendar year – though the way in which the crime is recorded means this may even be an underestimate of the scale of the problem.</p> <p>Much of this criminal activity was enabled by the internet, leading to calls from <span>some former police insiders for more public money to be handed to law enforcement to recruit the brightest IT brains.</span></p> <p>NAO chief Sir Amyas Morse said: <span>“</span>For too long, as a low-value but high-volume crime, online<span> fraud</span> has been overlooked by government, law enforcement and industry. It is now the most commonly experienced crime in England and Wales and demands an urgent response.<span>”</span></p> <p><span>The Home Office’s response currently is “not proportionate”, an NAO report, released today, also stated. It said there was a lack of data on how many fraudsters are convicted annually and the sentences they receive. The NAO also said the way in which banks work together to respond to scams needed to be beefed up, and it called for greater cross-border coordination by police.<br /></span><br /> Chris Hobbs, a former Metropolitan Police officer with contacts inside the Greater London force, which is Britain<span>’</span>s largest, told <em>E&amp;T</em>: “The problem, I think, comes down to resources and money. There’s been a lot of talk about employing civilian staff, very much like what the Serious Fraud Office was doing. I think there’s a huge case for employing civilian staff with expertise in cybercrime to work under the auspices of the police, but the problem is, who’s going to pay for it?</p> <p>“If we want the best people, in terms of detection of online fraud, they are going to be picked up by the banks who also want the best and who can offer higher salaries. Ultimately it’s the police who are going to have to arrest people and put cases before the courts, though, which is not easy. A lot of online fraud emanates from abroad, which of course makes it extremely difficult from a British policing point of view. You can’t imagine your average detective constable in a small force being able to deal with a case about cyber fraud.”</p> <p><span>Hobbs, who has become a regular commentator on the police in national newspapers since retiring from the Met,</span> added: “The government has got to put its hand its pocket. The starting salary for a police constable outside of London is around £24,000 a year, while in London it’s about £28,000. Police forces just can’t compete with what the banks offer.”</p> <p>Though ‘white collar’ crime is viewed as less of a priority nationally than fighting terrorism or pursuing murderers and sex offenders, online fraud can be a serious business for organised criminals who often use their ill-gotten gains to fund other types of criminality which can have a physical, sometimes deadly, impact on people.</p> <p>City of London Police, which is funded partly by banks in the Square Mile, currently leads the charge in terms of tackling fraud. Reports can come via Action Fraud, but currently not all incidents are recorded as crimes, meaning the true scale may be far greater than the most recent data suggests.</p> <p>With ever greater numbers of people using cards to make payments online rather than in person, criminals have increasingly taken to stealing card details over the internet. One potential way of addressing this involves introducing new cards that can change their security code – the number on the back of the card – every hour to prevent the use of stolen card data. Greater use of biometrics for identity authentication has also in the past been proposed.</p> <p>The Home Office said the government was acting to tackle online<span> fraud</span> but acknowledged that more needed to be done.</p> <p><span>“</span>Tackling online<span> fraud</span> demands a collaborative and innovative response to keep pace with the emerging threat,<span>”</span> a spokesman said.<br /><br /><span>“</span>The Joint<span> Fraud</span> Taskforce is now working to develop a cross-industry strategic plan to specifically tackle<span> fraud</span> where a person's bank card is being<span> fraud</span>ulently used online or over the phone.<br /><br /><span>“</span>We are also working together to identify what makes a person susceptible to falling victim to<span> fraud</span> in order to reduce an individual's vulnerability to this.<span>”</span></p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Josh Loeb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 14:01:01 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ cybersecurity ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ cybersecurity ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ cyber-security ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/online-fraud-threat-must-rise-up-priorities-list-watchdog-declares/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
View from Brussels: Europe divided over nuclear future
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/divide-in-europe-over-the-extent-to-which-the-future-is-nuclear/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3885/pele-30-06-17psd.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131433086050000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3885/pele-30-06-17psd.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131433086050000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>People have a problem with nuclear, don’t they? I remember attending an energy conference where the most persuasive debater argued that people’s fear about life is constant and when the immediate needs of food and shelter are taken care of this constant anxiety finds its outlet in something more abstract – and he quoted nuclear power as something that kept people awake at night. The corollary of this was that the fear was not rational.</p> <p>Some countries in Europe are more anti-nuclear than others. Germany has found rectitude in its decision to abandon nuclear power in 2011. Some say that this has been positive in that Germany’s decision has prompted China into a huge programme of investment into cheaper solar panel production, which has created a self-fulfilling demand, leading to lower thresholds for adopting sustainable energy. Other experts have said solar panels create their own problems with e-waste and that the dramatic claims made for growth in renewable energy should be taken with a pinch of salt.</p> <p>A group of scientists writing in the <em>Proceedings of the National Academy of Sciences*</em> rebut the claim that the US can generate its energy exclusively from wind, water and solar energy by the year 2050.   They warn that studies reaching this conclusion used “invalid modelling tools, contained modelling errors and made implausible and inadequately supported assumptions.” And the scientists warned policymakers to “treat with caution any visions of a rapid, reliable, and low-cost transition to entire energy systems that rely almost exclusively on wind solar and hydro-power.” Are you listening, Mrs Merkel?</p> <p>I think some of Germany’s neighbours believe that the country  uses bullying methods in the name of what would be loosely called politically correct ideas. But it’s the same old German empire, innit? Power abhors a vacuum and maybe this is the consequence of Britain withdrawing from Europe.  The Germans have looked with irritation upon their western and eastern neighbours’ continued use of nuclear power.</p> <p>France is too big and important to dictate to, but Belgium, one of whose nuclear reactors, Tihange 2,  is near the border, has had to endure protests. For instance, the mayor of Aachen has called for the closure of the plant and last week there was a human chain of 50,000 people, standing hand-in-hand across the Dutch, Belgian and German borders, calling for Belgium to close down its ageing plants. Recent news reports revealing how Belgian nuclear plants had thousands of micro-cracks surely didn’t do anything to calm German worries, even though they are said not to represent a serious risk.</p> <p>And then there are the Central and East European countries, who not only don’t want to let in refugees but persist in the modernist belief about the miracles of nuclear power. Nuclear power is said to be almost a religion, sources say, and there is little or no public discussion of investment risk or safety issues. The main problem seems to be who is going to stump up the enormous initial investment for new plants. As nuclear power is central to the Czech Republic’s energy policy, this topic is expected to be a major issue in the election later this year. Even in Poland, with its big coal-mining lobby, public opinion is strongly in favour of nuclear power. There remains a sense of prestige associated with nuclear projects and some argue such support can be attributed back to the Communist era, when the state ran the nuclear industry and surrounded it with an image of a futuristic plenitude for everyone. There were jobs, security, energy and stability for all, symbolised by the monoliths that were the nuclear plants. As we live in an age of insecurity and rapid change, perhaps the mythology of that stable past becomes ever more alluring.</p> <p>So here we have a study in contrasts. The big power in the region, Germany, is marching ahead with renewable energy while the countries that were devoted to the social experiment of communism two generations ago now not only seem to be conservative on issues like the traditional family, gay rights and hostility to mass immigration, but, dammit, they also prefer the tried-and-tested energy supply of nuclear power.</p> <p>Enthusiasts for solar power could, though, point to other reports such as one by Bloomberg New Energy Finance which predicts a 60-80 per cent drop in total costs by 2040, and the fact that solar is expected to  become cheaper than coal in just a few years, at $60/MWh. At some point after, solar will be competitive with natural gas.  The report also predicts that hundreds of billions of dollars will be invested in lithium-ion batteries, reducing perhaps the chief problem associated with renewables, which is their intermittency. The cost of onshore wind farms could also drop by more than two-thirds. Even so, the boosterish Bloomberg New Energy Finance report still predicts that nuclear and hydro will form as great a proportion of the world’s energy mix in 2040 as solar and wind: about a third.  </p> <p>I have always been a supporter of nuclear power, without being an expert, mainly because the hostility of the sceptics seemed to be based on such emotionally and apocalyptically non-rational reasons. Everyone I talk to believes far more people died at Chernobyl than actually did.</p> <p>But maybe, in so doing, I have underestimated the rapid innovation in solar technology driven by Germany’s about-turn after the Fukushima incident in 2011.  In that case,  Merkel’s <em>Energiewende</em> move was a brilliant piece of  political intuition that will change the world.  Will Merkel’s Refugees Welcome policy – which I believe contributed to the British turn away from Europe – also prove to be farsighted? I don’t believe it will prove to be so, but who can be sure.</p> <p><span style="font-size: 1rem;">*<a href="http://www.pnas.org/content/114/26/6722.full" target="_blank" title="http://www.pnas.org/content/114/26/6722.full">http://www.pnas.org/content/114/26/6722.full</a></span></p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Pelle Neroth ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 13:24:41 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ view from brussels ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ energy ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/divide-in-europe-over-the-extent-to-which-the-future-is-nuclear/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Merkel lambasts dodgy diesel automakers amid falling sales
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/merkel-lambasts-dodgy-diesel-automakers-amid-falling-sales/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3880/dreamstime_xl_60364078.jpg?center=0.42585551330798477,0.49275362318840582&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131432979680000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3880/dreamstime_xl_60364078.jpg?center=0.42585551330798477,0.49275362318840582&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131432979680000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>In an interview with the <em>Wirtschaftswoche</em> magazine published on Thursday, Merkel did not give a clear commitment to the diesel technology that her government has promoted to help cut carbon dioxide emissions and fight climate change.</p> <p>“What is important is that the newest and best technology is used,” she was quoted as saying. “We are in a transformation phase away from the combustion engine.”</p> <p>Merkel’s comments – almost two years after the Volkswagen emissions scandal broke – come as her government faces growing pressure ahead of national elections on 24 September to reduce diesel pollution or see cities impose driving bans.</p> <p>Sales of diesel cars have been falling since the VW scandal, but have dropped faster since cities, including Stuttgart and Munich, have considered banning some diesel vehicles, blaming emissions for a rise in respiratory disease.</p> <p>On Tuesday, German ministers announced they would establish a national “diesel forum” to find ways to cut pollution and set up a new organisation to test vehicles.</p> <p>On Wednesday, German carmakers BMW, Audi and truck manufacturer MAN agreed with the regional government in Bavaria to cut nitrogen oxide (NOx) emissions from diesel engines, a likely precursor to the national plan.</p> <p>Foreign carmakers have not yet committed to cutting emissions but will likely do so by the meeting of the government’s diesel forum on 2 August.</p> <p>Germany’s ADAC car club, Europe’s largest and most influential, has warned consumers to push back planned purchases of diesel cars until cleaner Euro-6D technology becomes available in new models this autumn.</p> <p>Merkel said how fast the shift away from combustion engines took place had to be negotiated, with efficient combustion engines likely to still have a long future, perhaps combined with electric motors in hybrid cars.</p> <p>Last month, she admitted Germany was likely to miss the government’s target of bringing one million electric cars onto the roads by the end of the decade, but added the breakthrough could come very abruptly, as with the smartphone.</p> <p>Merkel, who has been criticised by environmental and consumer groups for defending the diesel industry since the VW scandal, hit out at manufacturers that cheat emissions tests.</p> <p>“There is nothing that can justify the fraudulent methods used to limit test values in the diesel area of some manufacturers that has damaged the whole diesel business,” she said.</p> <p>“For many years we have appreciated diesel because it helped save fuel and CO2,” she said, adding some things had to be re-evaluated.</p> <p>Last month the software mechanism used in VW vehicles to artificially lower their emissions output when being tested by regulators <a href="/content/articles/2017/05/smoking-gun-found-in-volkswagen-s-vehicle-software-used-to-evade-regulators/" target="_blank">was discovered by a team</a> of international researchers. </p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Jack Loughran ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 13:09:05 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ vwgate ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ automotive ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ germany ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/merkel-lambasts-dodgy-diesel-automakers-amid-falling-sales/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Stable quantum computing closer to reality with new material
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/stable-quantum-computing-closer-to-reality-with-new-material/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3879/quantum-computer.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131432975880000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3879/quantum-computer.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131432975880000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>Quantum computing harnesses the power of superposition, a common sense-defying subatomic phenomena, to perform calculations far faster than current computers.</p> <p>In theory, in a quantum computer, qubits (quantum bits) can exist in both states (0 and 1) at the same moment. Information is encoded using these quantum states, although these quantum states are highly unstable and prone to collapsing with the slightest nudge.</p> <p>Adding an insulator could protect these states long enough for quantum operations to be completed. This could allow for much faster and stronger encryption and decryption, and the modelling of complex scientific systems – which are currently impossible to process, in just minutes.</p> <p>The research began at the University of Pennsylvania when, during his PhD, Dr Jerome Mlack was working with topological insulators (insulators which carry current only along their surfaces) and a device blew up.</p> <p>“It kind of melted a little bit,” said Dr Mlack. “What we found is that, if we measured the resistance of this melted region of one of these devices, it became superconducting. Then, when we went back and looked at what happened to the material and tried to find out what elements were in there, we only saw bismuth selenide and palladium.”</p> <p>Superconducting materials – which can carry current with no resistance at low temperatures – have been predicted to be useful components of fault-tolerant quantum computers when used with topological insulators. Despite this promise, it has proved extremely difficult to achieve electrical contact between insulator and superconductor, with a crack between the materials often reducing electrical contact.</p> <p>Dr Mlack’s accidentally melted device, however, achieved contact between the insulator and superconductor. Using a furnace, he was able to recreate this material with no contact problems.</p> <p>“The metal directly enters the nanostructure, providing good electrical contact and can be easily patterned into the nanostructure using standard lithography, allowing for easy scalability of custom superconducting circuits in a topological insulator.”</p> <p>The device is potentially scalable, meaning that it could be made to fit onto a small chip capable of fitting inside a desktop computer.</p> <p>“It really is a new potential way of fabricating these devices that no one has done before,” said Dr Mlack. “In general, when people make some of these materials by combining this topological material and superconductivity, it is a bulk crystal, so you don’t really control where everything is.</p> <p>“Here we can actually customise the pattern that we’re making into the material itself. That’s the most exciting part, especially when we start talking about adding in different types of metals that give it different characteristics.”</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Hilary Lamb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 13:01:06 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ quantum computing ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ electronic materials ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/stable-quantum-computing-closer-to-reality-with-new-material/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Instagram launches AI tools to combat extremism; Facebook’s internet drones take flight
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/instagram-launches-ai-tools-to-combat-extremism-facebook-s-internet-drones-take-flight/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3878/dreamstime_xl_31615952.jpg?center=0.55263157894736847,0.49570200573065903&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131432939630000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3878/dreamstime_xl_31615952.jpg?center=0.55263157894736847,0.49570200573065903&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131432939630000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The Facebook-owned platform said the AI filters have been “trained” to identify and block comments from appearing underneath posts if they are recognised as either offensive or spam-related.</p> <p>A button is being added to the app’s settings under the Comments section, enabling users to t
]]>
<![CDATA[
urn on the comment blocker.</p> <p>“Powered by machine learning, today’s filters are our latest tools to keep Instagram a safe place,” Instagram chief executive Kevin Systrom wrote in a blog post.</p> <p>“Our team has been training our systems for some time to recognise certain types of offensive and spammy comments so you never have to see them.</p> <p>“The tools will improve over time, enabling the community’s experience of sharing to improve as well. We hope to make these filters available in more languages as our algorithms improve.”</p> <p>Social media giants Facebook and Twitter have been among those criticised by the Government in recent months over their response to hate-filled and extreme content on their platforms, something both have pledged to improve. Earlier this week, along with YouTube and Microsoft, they agreed to form <a href="/content/articles/2017/06/social-media-giants-form-working-group-to-combat-extremism-online/" target="_blank">a global working group</a> to combine their efforts to remove terrorist content from their platforms. </p> <p>“We believe that using machine learning to build tools to safeguard self-expression is an important step in fostering more inclusive, kinder communities,” Systrom said.</p> <p>“Our work is far from finished and perfect, but I hope we’re helping you feel safer and more welcome on Instagram.”</p> <p>Meanwhile, Facebook has completed a second test of an unmanned aircraft designed to beam internet access to remote parts of the planet, and unlike in the first test, the drone did not crash.</p> <p>Facebook plans to develop a fleet of drones powered by sunlight that will fly for months at a time, communicating with each other through lasers and extending internet connectivity to the ground below.</p> <p>The company called the first test, in June 2016, a success after it flew above the Arizona desert for 1 hour and 36 minutes, three times longer than planned. It later said the drone had also crashed moments before landing and had suffered a damaged wing.</p> <p>The second test occurred on 22 May, Martin Luis Gomez, Facebook’s director of aeronautical platforms, said in a blog post. The aircraft flew for an hour and 46 minutes before landing near Yuma, Arizona, with only “a few minor, easily-repairable dings,” he said.</p> <p>Facebook engineers had added spoilers to the aircraft’s wings to increase drag and reduce lift during the landing approach, Gomez said.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Jack Loughran ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 12:01:59 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ facebook ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ social networks ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/instagram-launches-ai-tools-to-combat-extremism-facebook-s-internet-drones-take-flight/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Glass-based nuclear threat detectors prove stable and effective
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/glass-based-nuclear-threat-detectors-prove-stable-and-effective/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3877/scintillators-comparison.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131432933240000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3877/scintillators-comparison.jpg?crop=0,0.50828125,0,0&cropmode=percentage&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131432933240000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>Scintillators, which produce bright light when struck by radiation, are used extensively by the US Government in homeland security as radiation detectors. By observing the amount of light produced, and how quickly, the source of radiation may be identified.</p> <p>Dr Patrick Feng, who led the Defense Nuclear Nonproliferation project, began to develop new types of scintillators in 2010, in order to “strengthen national security by improving the cost-to-performance ratio of radiation detectors”. To improve this ratio, he had to “bridge the gap” between effective scintillators made from expensive materials, and affordable but far less effective models.</p> <p>Although there are many types of scintillator available, the best-performing scintillators are made from trans-stilbene. This crystallised form of a molecule allows border security tell the difference between gamma rays, which appear naturally everywhere, and neutrons, which are often associated with threatening materials such as plutonium and uranium, by producing a bright light in response.</p> <p>These crystals, however, are too fragile and expensive to be used in the field, and instead, security personnel will tend to use plastic-based scintillators, which can be moulded into large shapes but are ineffective at differentiating between different types of radiation or detecting weak sources.</p> <p>In order to find a good alternative, Dr Feng and his team at Sandia National Laboratories in Livermore, CA, began to experiment with organic glass components, which are capable of discriminating between different types of radiation.</p> <p>Tests demonstrated that scintillators made with organic glass performed even better than the trans-stilbene scintillators in radiation detection tests.</p> <p>The researchers were able to improve their design further when they drew a parallel between the behaviour of LEDs, which produce light when electrical energy is applied, and scintillators, which respond to radioactive sources. They found that adding fluorine, which is used in some LEDs, into the scintillator components helped stabilise them. This allowed for the organic glass to be melted down and cast into large blocks without becoming cloudy or crystallising upon cooling.</p> <p>The result was an indefinitely stable scintillator able to differentiate between non-threatening radioactive sources, such as those used in medical treatments, and those which could constitute threats. The organic glass components are cheap and easy to manufacture, and do not degrade over time.</p> <p>Next, the researchers will cast a large prototype for field testing, and hopefully demonstrate that the scintillator can withstand environmental wear and tear, for instance, due to the humidity of ports where checks are carried out. They also hope to adjust the scintillator to distinguish between safe sources of gamma radiation, and those which could be used to make “dirty bombs”.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Hilary Lamb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 11:50:42 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ security in the modern world ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ product development ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ nuclear ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/glass-based-nuclear-threat-detectors-prove-stable-and-effective/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[ Formula E unlikely to return to London this year ]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/formula-e-unlikely-to-return-to-london-this-year/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3876/eprix.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131432931110000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3876/eprix.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131432931110000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>London is almost certain to sit out fourth season of the world’s first fully electric single-seater motor racing series, despite <span>Battersea Park having previously hosted successful races</span>, <em>E&amp;T</em> understands.</p> <p>No competitive events involving the environmentally friendly vehicles are scheduled to take place in the city, and insiders regard it as highly unlikely that there still remains enough time to organise any such event for the <span>2017-18 season.</span></p> <p>Plans are afoot for a “wow factor” electric motorsport fixture in the UK capital during the 2018-19 season, however, and returning to the city is considered a top priority by organisers Formula E because of London<span>’s</span> global clout.</p> <p>When the list of locations for this season<span>’</span>s fixtures was made public earlier this month, London was notable by its absence. The organisers had hoped electric cars would be allowed to race down some of the most iconic streets in the city to boost the exposure of electric mobility and drive ticket sales.</p> <p>Permission for such a high-profile event, which would have been likely to draw big crowds, appears not to have materialised in time, though. Such events are tightly regulated, and numerous authorities including councils, the fire service and the Mayor of London’s office would have had to give their blessing.</p> <p>This season’s calendar features what organisers describe as “a more compact schedule than in previous years”, including three double-headers and three new venues - Santiago, Sao Paulo and Rome.</p> <p>Formula E will stop at new locations in both South America and Europe this season, with races in the Chilean capital Santiago in February and on the streets of Sao Paulo in March.</p> <p>The electric street-racing series will also be holding an event in Rome and will be returning to the French capital for the third edition of the Paris ePrix on April 28 2018.</p> <p>The penultimate event will take place in New York against the backdrop of Manhattan skyscrapers and the Statue of Liberty, before the season draws to a close in Montreal, Canada, next summer.</p> <p>FIA President Jean Todt, said: “The FIA Formula E Championship continues to break new ground bringing motorsport and electric mobility to new urban centres around the world.”</p> <p>He added: “The impact of this exposure to millions of potential new fans will be fantastic, and the desire of the cities to be involved in the championship shows how much of a success Formula E has been over its first three seasons.”</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Josh Loeb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 11:33:54 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ electric vehicles ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/formula-e-unlikely-to-return-to-london-this-year/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
HPC simulation: a resourceful route from the drawing board to the driveway
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/hpc-simulation-a-resourceful-route-from-the-drawing-board-to-the-driveway/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3874/car-design.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131432874950000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3874/car-design.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131432874950000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>High-performance computer (HPC) simulation using computer-aided engineering (CAE) applications has evolved from a tool once used by automakers for limited-use cases in the vehicle design process to improving and optimising all aspects of product development, including the manufacturing process. It is now common for the same CAE simulation tools to analyse and determine the most efficient and cost-effective manufacturing processes.</p> <p>Widely used for sheet metal stamping simulations, HPC simulation removes inefficiencies from the eventual manufacturing process by preventing potential defects such as metal wrinkles. Simulation has become especially valuable as new materials such as aluminium and plastics are introduced, enabling manufacturers to avoid the expensive inefficiencies of the traditional trial and error approach to establishing the production process of a new vehicle.</p> <p>As new materials are implemented for the advancement of vehicle design, manufacturers can no longer depend on the experience and expertise that they traditionally relied upon to understand the extents to which these new materials can be manipulated. HPC simulation is essential in enabling manufacturers to understand what can be achieved with these materials and can predict the final shape of a new component through the digital replication of material properties.</p> <p><strong>Driving up the data flow</strong></p> <p>Throughout the automotive industry there is growing demand for data gathered during manufacturing simulation that can be used to improve the finalised design of a vehicle.</p> <p>To achieve a higher fidelity in results, it is no longer adequate to use nominal or average material properties for individual components. The structural properties and tolerances of the material will change as the material is manipulated throughout the vehicle’s production, therefore it is more accurate to use the final material properties of the component after the manufacturing process.</p> <p>For example, the simulation results of a piece of sheet metal being bent into a certain shape, such as a body panel, can provide the material’s stress and strain state without a physical piece of metal having to be bent. With high-fidelity crash simulation, the slight difference in material properties before and after stamping will affect the crash response, so including this effect will deliver a more accurate simulation.</p> <p>The results speak for themselves, and so there is now a growing requirement for increased communication between teams working on different stages of the manufacturing process and the flow of data from the manufacturing process back into the vehicle CAE analysis process.</p> <p><strong>The stochastic approach for a robust design</strong></p> <p>Accounting for the variation in the real-world structure after manufacturing has led to the use of a ‘stochastic approach’ in CAE simulation. In other words, a robust design approach that ensures the final product is highly resilient against slight variations that result from the manufacturing process.</p> <p>A good example of this is the location of spot welds in the vehicle’s construction, commonly used to connect large components in the structure, such as the floor pan and the body shell. It has been shown that even the slightest variation – including variations within manufacturing tolerances – in the location of a spot weld can have a major impact on the safety performance of the finished vehicle.</p> <p>To understand the sensitivity of the design, a stochastic simulation process runs hundreds of simulations, which vary the parameter of interest. Comparing the results allows the manufacturer to determine the sensitivity of the design to the spot weld location or other parameters. Understanding this sensitivity enables a more robust vehicle design, which reduces the risk of failing a safety test due to the slight variations in manufacturing.</p> <p>This robust design does require an investment in HPC compute power. The stochastic investigation of a single component in a vehicle’s design requires hundreds of simulations and, for each of these simulations to run simultaneously, a greater amount of computing is required. The computing requirements have traditionally been a limiting factor in adopting the stochastic approach but the increased availability in HPC power now makes this practical for automobile design and production processes to run more efficiently.</p> <p><strong>Reinventing the wheelbase</strong></p> <p>Further development lays in the synergy between manufacturing technology and CAE simulations – the results of which advance additive manufacturing technology and the use of topology optimisation tools. For example, topological optimisation might generate a more organically shaped vehicle component that could be shaped similarly to a human bone to add more strength and resilience, while reducing the weight of a traditional structural component such as an I-beam.</p> <p>Topology optimisation has been available for many years, but in the past, this approach required a huge amount of computing power and the final ‘optimised’ design would have a very complex shape that would be impractical to manufacture.</p> <p>Today, additive manufacturing processes make it reasonable to produce these very complex parts and the increase in computing power makes the amount of simulations required far easier to achieve. The combination of these technology advancements creates an entirely new set of design possibilities and will play a key role in industry initiatives such as vehicle weight reduction.</p> <p><strong>Souped-up data performance</strong></p> <p>Not only are we seeing a huge increase in the amount of data available but also in the requirement to share this data throughout the organisation. Simulation is producing high-fidelity results for a wide-range of design options while manufacturing process and tools are producing highly valuable data. In some cases, data is also being streamed back to the manufacturer via the Internet of Things (IoT) once the vehicle is on the road.</p> <p>Incorporating sensors that can relay information back to manufacturers contributes to the wealth of information on the past, current and potentially the future performance of the vehicle, or similar models and conceptual designs based on the same vehicle platform.</p> <p>Clearly there is a tremendous amount of value in this data and the ability to analyse this, finding the patterns and gaining actionable information, is an aim every automaker wishes to fulfil. The challenge lies in recognising what to look for and how to find this value in the enormity and variety of data available.</p> <p>Just like supercomputing power has enabled the simulation of the vehicle design and manufacturing, that same power can be applied to the data analytics challenge and is opening up a new field of high-performance data analytics (HPDA).</p> <p>Although still a relatively new field, automotive companies are making huge investments in data analytics. There is no shortage of potential use cases, from spotting warranty or recall issues earlier, to optimising the manufacturing processes, developing better understanding of industry trends and learning about evolutions in consumer requirements.</p> <p>These are not necessarily new concepts but the technology available is evolving rapidly. While implementation in production infrastructure remains a work in progress, the uptake throughout the automotive industry is likely to gather pace sooner rather than later. Much like the increased adoption of vehicle electronics, autonomous driving and other industry trends, HPDA will redefine the technology and the associated skills required to compete in the automotive industry.</p> <p><em>Greg Clifford is the manufacturing segment leader at CRAY.</em></p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Greg Clifford ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Fri, 30 Jun 2017 10:11:06 +0000</pubDate>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/hpc-simulation-a-resourceful-route-from-the-drawing-board-to-the-driveway/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Apple iPhone 10th anniversary: a timeline of the landmark device
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/apple-iphone-10th-anniversary-a-timeline-of-the-landmark-device/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3872/jobs.jpg?center=0.3611111111111111,0.35978835978835977&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131432248480000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3872/jobs.jpg?center=0.3611111111111111,0.35978835978835977&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131432248480000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The impact of the iPhone cannot be understated. Its release kick-started a new technological era focused on apps, social media and an endless fascination with photographing and documenting one’s daily life.</p> <p>Although it wasn’t the first device to contain a touchscreen, a camera or mobil
]]>
<![CDATA[
e internet functionality, it was the first to combine all of these in a way that felt futuristic and, most importantly of all, intuitive.</p> <p>Steve Jobs finally unveiled the iPhone in a keynote address at the Macworld Conference in California on 9 January 2007 after a protracted two-and-a-half-year development cycle.</p> <p>“Today, Apple is going to reinvent the phone,” he proclaimed, introducing it as a combination of three devices: a “widescreen iPod with touch controls”, a “revolutionary mobile phone”, and a “breakthrough Internet communicator”.</p> <p>What Jobs held in his hand that day was a prototype device with limited functionality and hundreds of bugs, spanning issues related to both hardware and software.</p> <p>Most (but not all) of these bugs were ironed out over the next six months in order to meet the anticipated shipping date for consumers.</p> <p>The iPhone has gone through many iterations in the intervening years, with every element improved upon and the experience made consistently slicker and more refined. The basic template set by the original device has remained largely unchanged, though, and has been used by a far broader subset of companies than just Apple, most notably in the hundreds of Android devices that are now on the market today.</p> <h3>iPhone (2007)</h3> <p>The first generation model straddled a weird line between old and new technology. It included a multi-touch capacitive touchscreen that didn’t need a stylus to operate – the user’s finger would do, a revolutionary concept at the time.</p> <p>It included Wi-Fi and a browser that was capable of rendering full web pages with no compromises.</p> <p>Unfortunately, for a device that leaned so heavily on the possibilities of mobile internet, it only included a chip capable of picking up 2G mobile signal, leaving internet to load at a snail’s pace.</p> <figure class="article-image"> <picture> <source media="(min-width: 1200px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3867/iphone-1.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&rnd=131432248070000000"> <source media="(min-width: 960px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3867/iphone-1.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432248070000000"> <source media="(min-width 760px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3867/iphone-1.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=640&rnd=131432248070000000"> <source media="(min-width 320px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3867/iphone-1.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=320&rnd=131432248070000000"> <!-- fallback image for non supporting browsers --> <img class="img-responsive lazyload" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==" data-src="/media/3867/iphone-1.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432248070000000" /> </picture> <figcaption class="figure-caption fade-background"> <p class="image-caption">First generation iPhone</p> </figcaption> </figure> <p>Although even mid-range phones at the time were 3G enabled, the iPhone’s development cycle was so protracted that when they started in 2005 there simply wasn’t a chip that existed that was small enough to provide 3G functionality.</p> <p>It’s 2MP camera was acceptable for the time, but lacked any kind of video recording and the app store was nowhere to be found – that would come later.</p> <h3>iPhone 3G (2008)</h3> <p>As is evidenced by the name, Apple was keen to point out that the next iteration of the iPhone did finally include a 3G chip, one of the major shortcomings of the previous generation.</p> <p>Yet again it used an underwhelming 2MP pixel without native video recording functionality, a bizarre omission considering competing devices at the time.</p> <p>However, the iPhone 3G also launched with an App Store, smashing open the doors of what the device was capable of (including third-party video recording apps!). The App Store may have been underwhelming at first, featuring far too many fart noise and faux beer-drinking apps, but its popularity spread like wildfire, leading to developers quickly jumping on the app bandwagon.</p> <h3>iPhone 3GS (2009)</h3> <p>The 3GS may have mostly stuck to the same design as the preceding two models, but it housed a significantly faster processor (the S stands for speed) that provided a smoother experience and ensured that it was powerful enough to receive software updates for years to come.</p> <figure class="article-image"> <picture> <source media="(min-width: 1200px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3866/dreamstime_xl_40010287.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&rnd=131432247980000000"> <source media="(min-width: 960px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3866/dreamstime_xl_40010287.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432247980000000"> <source media="(min-width 760px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3866/dreamstime_xl_40010287.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=640&rnd=131432247980000000"> <source media="(min-width 320px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3866/dreamstime_xl_40010287.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=320&rnd=131432247980000000"> <!-- fallback image for non supporting browsers --> <img class="img-responsive lazyload" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==" data-src="/media/3866/dreamstime_xl_40010287.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432247980000000" /> </picture> <figcaption class="figure-caption fade-background"> <p class="image-caption">iPhone 3GS</p> </figcaption> </figure> <p>The camera was bumped to 3MP (with native video recording) and included a digital compass so that Google Maps could know which way you were facing.</p> <h3>iPhone 4 &amp; 4S (2010-2011)</h3> <p>The iPhone 4 saw Apple making some significant design changes in comparison to the previous generations.</p> <p>Gone were the rounded backs of the earlier models, to be replaced by straight clean lines that gave it a more modern look.</p> <p>Most impressively, it was the first device to include Apple’s “Retina” screen, a high-density display that eschewed the grainy look of older models.</p> <p>The development of the iPhone 4 became surprisingly public when a developer accidentally left a prototype model in a bar months before it was officially announced. The prototype fell into the hands of tech site Gizmodo, who did a teardown for the world to see - much to Apple’s chagrin, naturally.</p> <figure class="article-image"> <picture> <source media="(min-width: 1200px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3870/ipohne-4s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&rnd=131432248160000000"> <source media="(min-width: 960px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3870/ipohne-4s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432248160000000"> <source media="(min-width 760px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3870/ipohne-4s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=640&rnd=131432248160000000"> <source media="(min-width 320px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3870/ipohne-4s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=320&rnd=131432248160000000"> <!-- fallback image for non supporting browsers --> <img class="img-responsive lazyload" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==" data-src="/media/3870/ipohne-4s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432248160000000" /> </picture> <figcaption class="figure-caption fade-background"> <p class="image-caption">iPhone 4S</p> </figcaption> </figure> <p>Gizmodo was subsequently banned from all Apple events for several years.</p> <p>The iPhone 4S, released the year after, saw many elements of the 4 improved, including the camera and the processor, but failed to make any significant changes in comparison to the relatively seismic shift brought by the 4.</p> <h3>iPhone 5, iPhone 5S &amp; iPhone 5C (2012-2013)</h3> <p>While Apple may have started the smartphone trend, rivals were quick to emulate the success of the iPhone.</p> <p>Companies such as Samsung and Motorola were pumping out their own devices that typically featured a much larger screen. Although Steve Jobs had railed against the idea of making the iPhone bigger, stating that it wouldn’t be comfortable for one-handed use, market pressure saw Apple lengthen the iPhone 5 to a 4-inch display (while still keeping the same width).</p> <figure class="article-image"> <picture> <source media="(min-width: 1200px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3868/iphone-5.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&rnd=131432248090000000"> <source media="(min-width: 960px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3868/iphone-5.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432248090000000"> <source media="(min-width 760px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3868/iphone-5.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=640&rnd=131432248090000000"> <source media="(min-width 320px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3868/iphone-5.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=320&rnd=131432248090000000"> <!-- fallback image for non supporting browsers --> <img class="img-responsive lazyload" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==" data-src="/media/3868/iphone-5.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432248090000000" /> </picture> <figcaption class="figure-caption fade-background"> <p class="image-caption">iPhone 5 in black and white</p> </figcaption> </figure> <p>In addition to the larger screen, the iPhone 5 was the first to include the new “Lightning” connector in place of the chunky, ageing 30-pin connector that had been used to charge and connect every Apple device going back to the first USB iPod (the very early iPods were FireWire only).</p> <p>The Lightning connector was much smaller, reversible and less prone to failure, but criticism was received because it instantly consigned millions of accessories using the older connector to the dustbin.</p> <p>The iPhone 5S’s most significant improvement, along with the typical processor and camera upgrades, was the addition of Touch ID, a fingerprint recognition system used to unlock the phone that has become a mainstay in later models.</p> <p>The iPhone 5C was also introduced, a budget offering enclosed in a plastic case, rather than a metal case, and based on the previous generation device. Although doing well initially, it failed to set the world on fire and the range was quietly discontinued in 2015.</p> <figure class="article-image"> <picture> <source media="(min-width: 1200px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3873/3g-4-5s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&rnd=131432248230000000"> <source media="(min-width: 960px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3873/3g-4-5s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432248230000000"> <source media="(min-width 760px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3873/3g-4-5s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=640&rnd=131432248230000000"> <source media="(min-width 320px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3873/3g-4-5s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=320&rnd=131432248230000000"> <!-- fallback image for non supporting browsers --> <img class="img-responsive lazyload" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==" data-src="/media/3873/3g-4-5s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432248230000000" /> </picture> <figcaption class="figure-caption fade-background"> <p class="image-caption">In order left to right: iPhone 3G, 4, 5S</p> </figcaption> </figure> <h3>iPhone 6, 6S &amp; SE (2014-2015)</h3> <p>The iPhone 6 saw Apple finally embracing modern smartphone trends by expanding the base model to a 4.7 inch screen and introducing the “Plus” variant that included a 5.5 inch screen.</p> <p>The new displays saw Apple revamp the aspect ratios of the screen, although still maintaining the “Retina” functionality of older models (something that was less impressive by 2014).</p> <p>It was also the first to add near-field communication (NFC), which allowed payments to be made via Apple Pay.</p> <p>As is now tradition, the 6S changed little from the previous design, although it did include a new hardware feature called “3D Touch” that allowed users to exert additional pressure on the screen in order to trigger “right-click” functionality and “peek” at content without switching to a separate app, such as viewing a photo attachment in an e-mail without actually switching to the Photos app.</p> <figure class="article-image"> <picture> <source media="(min-width: 1200px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3869/iphone-6s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&rnd=131432248130000000"> <source media="(min-width: 960px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3869/iphone-6s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432248130000000"> <source media="(min-width 760px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3869/iphone-6s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=640&rnd=131432248130000000"> <source media="(min-width 320px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3869/iphone-6s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=320&rnd=131432248130000000"> <!-- fallback image for non supporting browsers --> <img class="img-responsive lazyload" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==" data-src="/media/3869/iphone-6s.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432248130000000" /> </picture> <figcaption class="figure-caption fade-background"> <p class="image-caption">iPhone 6S</p> </figcaption> </figure> <p>During this time Apple also released the iPhone SE, basically an update to the iPhone 5 due to continued demand from some consumers for a smaller device.</p> <h3>iPhone 7 (2016)</h3> <p>The iPhone 7, Apple’s latest handset, included a few new features including full water and dust-proofing and a new capacitive, static home button.</p> <p>Controversially, Apple chose to remove the 3.5mm headphone jack for the first time meaning that users were obliged to either use Bluetooth headphones or the included wired adapter if they wanted to use the device to listen to music. The jury is still out on whether this trend will be replicated across the smartphone industry.</p> <p>The iPhone 7 Plus included a dual-camera system that added an optical 2X zoom, a first for smartphones (although others quickly followed suit).</p> <figure class="article-image"> <picture> <source media="(min-width: 1200px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3871/ipohne-7.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&rnd=131432248180000000"> <source media="(min-width: 960px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3871/ipohne-7.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432248180000000"> <source media="(min-width 760px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3871/ipohne-7.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=640&rnd=131432248180000000"> <source media="(min-width 320px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3871/ipohne-7.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=320&rnd=131432248180000000"> <!-- fallback image for non supporting browsers --> <img class="img-responsive lazyload" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==" data-src="/media/3871/ipohne-7.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432248180000000" /> </picture> <figcaption class="figure-caption fade-background"> <p class="image-caption">iPhone 7</p> </figcaption> </figure> <h3>The future</h3> <p>Rumours are swirling as to what Apple will do for the tenth anniversary of its most popular device.</p> <p>The company is clearly interested in making a big deal of the iPhone 8, with early leaks suggesting it may get rid of the home button altogether and embed the front-facing camera and fingerprint scanner underneath an edge-to-edge screen in a similar fashion to recent devices from rival manufacturers Samsung and LG.</p> <p>It may also include wireless charging for the first time, which could see the technology finally enter the mainstream years after its first appearance on some Android devices.</p> <p>Apple is also rumoured to be looking into updating its displays to use OLED technology, which is typically brighter and has a superior contrast ratio in comparison to LED technology.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Jack Loughran ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 16:55:18 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ apple ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ consumer technology ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ smartphones ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ jack loughran ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ gadgets ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/apple-iphone-10th-anniversary-a-timeline-of-the-landmark-device/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Weibo capitulates amid Chinese government’s censorship crackdown
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/weibo-capitulates-amid-chinese-government-s-censorship-crackdown/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3629/dreamstime_xl_37953679.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131411506540000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3629/dreamstime_xl_37953679.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131411506540000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The firm behind China’s top microblogging site indicated it would prefer to self-censor rather than be forcibly closed, saying in a statement released late last night that it would work with state media, such as the Xinhua news agency and the People’s Daily, to promote a <span>“</span>mainstream<span>”</span> discourse in future.</p> <p>Unlicensed television and film content, as well as videos longer than 15 minutes, will also be banned on its platforms, Weibo said.</p> <p>The announcement comes just days after Weibo published a press release acknowledging receipt of a notice issued to it by the state media regulator which threatened to close its hugely popular video-sharing service along with two other popular rivals, AcFun and Ifeng.</p> <p>Thousands of journalists have also reportedly been fired amid the latest crackdown on freedom of expression.<br /> <br /> In a statement posted on its website yesterday, Weibo said it <span>“</span>sincerely accepted<span>”</span> criticism from the regulator and would immediately begin work to remove political, media and current affairs video accounts from outlets which lack the appropriate government-issued license.</p> <p>All forms of media are strictly controlled in China and the government has previously vowed to further strengthen its control over the dissemination of information to the public.</p> <p>Beijing has long feared that tittle-tattle about Chinese Communist Party officials, spread through social media, could stoke civil unrest and the Party appears to have been shaken by the scale of the appetite in the country for vlogging and microblogging – a phenomenon which is now becoming increasingly mired in red tape.</p> <p>Television and film producers in China are legally required to submit content to the state regulator for approval. Streams deemed harmful to morality are swiftly shut down.</p> <p>In recent years the Chinese government has particularly taken against apps which allow users to live-stream video content. In 2014, online video platform LeTV began removing its app that allows TV users to access online video, reportedly because of requirements laid down by the State Administration of Press, Publication, Radio, Film and Television.</p> <p><span>Earlier this year the Chinese government blocked millions of overseas users of Weibo from posting pictures or video on their feeds to mark the 28th anniversary of the Tiananmen Square massacre.</span></p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Josh Loeb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 16:24:04 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ engineering and technology in society ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ internet ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ privacy ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ china ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/weibo-capitulates-amid-chinese-government-s-censorship-crackdown/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Pepper robot transformed to care for patients with brain injuries
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/pepper-robot-transformed-to-care-for-patients-with-brain-injuries/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3865/retogar.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131432204770000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3865/retogar.jpg?crop=0,0.48416666666666669,0,0.023645833333333265&cropmode=percentage&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131432204770000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>Caring for patients with neurological injuries as they gradually recover and readjust to ordinary life requires almost constant attention. Sociable robots could potentially reduce the workload of nurses and other healthcare professionals by assisting these patients.</p> <p>Computer scientists from the University of Alicante, Spain, have been attempting to develop a robotic system to help with this work.</p> <p>The Retogar project began in January and will continue through 2018 and 2019. It is a continuation of a project completed in 2016, which led to the creation of a multi-sensor device capable of adapting to the needs of patients with different motor and cognitive disabilities.</p> <p>The ongoing project is focused around the development of a sociable robot which can interact with a patient during rehabilitation.</p> <div class="responsive-media video"> <iframe width="560" height="315" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/gHuOMU9yEJ4" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe> </div> <p>The researchers are working with an existing robot, Pepper, a friendly-looking robot created by SoftBank and Alderbaran Robotics. Pepper can read some emotions, analysing facial expression and tone of voice. While Pepper is not available as a domestic companion, it is used as a research robot and its creators have stated that they hope other developers will create new uses for it.</p> <p>The University of Alicante team are pre-programming Pepper with behaviours and scenarios and will use natural language processing, visual attention and sound learning to help it understand commands and its surroundings.</p> <p>“Other than interacting with the patient, it would guide them with daily therapeutic exercises and activities such as taking medication or brushing their teeth,” said Professor Miguel Cazorla, an associate professor of computer science at the university.</p> <p>Geolocation sensors will detect high-risk situations within the home and outdoors and the robot will use sophisticated new sensors to identify motor difficulties, disorientation and reduced visibility of the patient; all complications that can follow brain injury. The robot will be able to send alerts when it detects risks.</p> <p>The researchers will also develop virtual reality applications and 3D interfaces for the patients.</p> <p>The resulting technology will be tested in household and outdoor scenarios with real patients with brain injuries, in collaboration with the Casaverde Foundation, which helps patients complete their neurological and physical rehabilitation.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Hilary Lamb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 15:52:30 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ rehabilitation and prosthetics ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ healthcare technologies ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ robots ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/pepper-robot-transformed-to-care-for-patients-with-brain-injuries/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Review: Henge Docks Gravitas iPhone 7, iPad Lightning dock
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/review-henge-docks-gravitas-iphone-7-ipad-lightning-dock/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3532/gravitas-main.jpg?center=0.768,0.50914634146341464&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131432218420000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3532/gravitas-main.jpg?center=0.768,0.50914634146341464&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131432218420000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>Apple is well known for its industrial design: the minimalist aesthetic, the attention to detail, the choice of materials, the quality of components, the overall imparting of a reassuring sense of quality and luxe appointment. Under the artistic direction of (Sir) Jony Ive, Apple has set the bar
]]>
<![CDATA[
high for its own products. What do these demands mean for other companies, those producing third-party accessories to accompany Apple’s own products?</p> <p>We recently talked with Matt Vroom, designer and founder of Henge Docks – a US company producing elegant docking solutions for Apple laptops and iOS devices – about what it means to create products for the Apple ecosystem and what creative challenges and opportunities are presented to the modern designer. This interview is below.</p> <p>Henge Docks presented a range of new docking products at CES 2017 in January, including both Horizontal and Vertical Docks for the MacBook Pro laptop and an all-new Tethered Dock. This new collection of docks allows the user to bring together all their Apple products into one integrated desktop setup, uniting laptop computer with external monitors, speakers, keyboards, track pads – pretty much anything you can plug in.</p> <p>With everything permanently connected, you can drop your laptop into place and be instantly connected, but also simply grab and go when you need to travel light.</p> <figure class="article-image"> <picture> <source media="(min-width: 1200px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3531/gravitas-design.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&rnd=131400214300000000"> <source media="(min-width: 960px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3531/gravitas-design.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131400214300000000"> <source media="(min-width 760px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3531/gravitas-design.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=640&rnd=131400214300000000"> <source media="(min-width 320px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3531/gravitas-design.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=320&rnd=131400214300000000"> <!-- fallback image for non supporting browsers --> <img class="img-responsive lazyload" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==" data-src="/media/3531/gravitas-design.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131400214300000000" /> </picture> </figure> <p>Docks are a big thing for Henge, large and small, and we’ve looked at Henge Docks’ latest Lightning charging dock for iPhones and iPads, on review here. It’s a similar grab and go philosophy, only with small and perfectly formed for iOS devices.</p> <p>Called the Gravitas, this dock is a weighty thing of minimalist beauty. Made of a sturdy zinc alloy more than 265 per cent more dense than aluminum and weighing 2.5lbs, Gravitas was designed to perfectly match the prevailing Apple aesthetic. Despite the weight, it is also delightfully small, only taking up approximately the same amount of desk space as a regular coffee mug.</p> <p>The idea behind Gravitas is that it sits permanently connected to your computer, so you don’t have to constantly fiddle with (and find) the right charging cable. Drop your iPhone onto the Dock and you’re done. When you need to go, grab your iPhone or iPad and the sheer weight of Gravitas will keep the dock on your desk as you safely pocket your device.</p> <p>Gravitas also has a line-out audio port, to which you can plug in powered speakers. In this way, Gravitas can act as an audio hub for any devices plugged in to it, routing the music or movie from whichever app is playing it on the device. The high-fidelity, fixed-volume, stereo audio output comes directly from the Lightning connector.</p> <p>Another nice touch is what Henge terms “life after device”. This refers to the swappable plastic insert trays that come with Gravitas, each of which is specific to any recent iOS device. Using the correct insert guarantees the best fit and docking experience. The inserts also have removeable inner liners, to fine-tune the fit for many slim-line cases.</p> <p>Looking to the future, the use of these inserts also means that your Gravitas investment won’t be instantly rendered worthless when Apple releases a new handset. Henge will release new inserts to suit new devices, so that’s the only part you'll need to replace. It’s a neat solution.</p> <figure class="article-image"> <picture> <source media="(min-width: 1200px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3530/gravitas-inserts.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&rnd=131400214280000000"> <source media="(min-width: 960px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3530/gravitas-inserts.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131400214280000000"> <source media="(min-width 760px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3530/gravitas-inserts.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=640&rnd=131400214280000000"> <source media="(min-width 320px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3530/gravitas-inserts.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=320&rnd=131400214280000000"> <!-- fallback image for non supporting browsers --> <img class="img-responsive lazyload" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==" data-src="/media/3530/gravitas-inserts.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131400214280000000" /> </picture> </figure> <p>Our only grumble is that the plastic inserts are, well, a bit plastic-y. We have a soft spot for soft-touch plastic and we wish more manufacturers invested that little bit extra for the uprated tactile experience. It would also be reassuring when constantly docking and undocking your expensive iPhone, knowing that the softer insert wasn’t going to be harming the phone’s finish. This is a minor point, though, and certainly not something unique to Henge.</p> <p>Depending on how many iOS devices you have in your home, you might not use the best insert all the time – e.g. you have an iPhone and an iPad, or other people in your house have older iPhones, or iPhones in sleeves and cases that bulk out their dimensions. You have options with Gravitas, at least, and popping out and swapping out the inserts is a simple task.</p> <p>Overall, Gravitas is impressive: solid, reliable, deceptively simple in appearance yet full-featured. You can literally use this Dock in the dark. With the appropriate insert in place, your device simply drops straight onto the Lightning connector, without fail. Without the perfect insert in place, you do have to be slightly more focused, but it’s still easy. Undocking it is a case of grab, pull and go. The Gravitas itself ain’t moving.</p> <p>It’s true that you are paying something of a premium for this experience, but once you become a consumer of Apple products and supplementary accessories, presumably you’re already on board with this and are relatively immune to sticker shock.</p> <p>This is not to say that Gravitas is over-priced; rather, it is what it is: a superb docking solution for Lightning-jack iPhones and iPads; one that is made of quality materials; which complements your existing hardware; that will never give you a moment’s trouble and can grow with you, rather than becoming obsolete overnight when a new product arrives. The total cost of ownership outweighs and outlasts the initial outlay. Kind of like one of Apple’s own products, in fact.</p> <h3>Tech spec</h3> <p>Ports</p> <p>    •    USB</p> <p>    •    3.5mm Stereo Audio Out</p> <p>Included in box</p> <p>    •    Gravitas Dock</p> <p>    •    iPhone 6/6s/7 Case Compatible Insert</p> <p>    •    iPhone 6 Plus/6s Plus/7 Plus/iPad Case Compatible Insert</p> <p>    •    3-foot USB Cable</p> <p>    •    User Guide</p> <p>Weights &amp; Dimensions</p> <p>    •    Product weight: 1.17 kg/2.54 lbs</p> <p>    •    Shipping weight: 1.50 kg/3.25 lbs</p> <p>    •    Product dimensions: 7.8 cm x 8.5 cm x 6.4 cm/3.0 in x 3.3 in x 2.5 in</p> <p>Price</p> <p>€79</p> <p><a href="https://hengedocks.com/" target="_blank">More about Henge Docks</a></p> <div class="panel panel-box-out"> <div class="panel-heading"> <div class="sub-head">Interview: Matt Vroom, founder Henge Docks</div> <h3>What is design?</h3> </div> <div class="panel-body"> <p>The following questions are taken from the list asked of designer Charles Eames in 1969 by Madame L'Amic, the curator of the Musée Arts Decoratifs in Paris. She asked five international designers participating in the exhibition 'Qu'est ce que le design?' ('What Is Design?') the same questions.</p> <p>We put 10 of Madame L'Amic's 1969 questions to Matt Vroom in 2017, asking him to consider his work as an industrial designer for Henge Docks and to reveal the creative thinking and approach to design that helps drive and shape his products.   </p> <p>    •    What is your definition of design?</p> <p>I view design as a process which facilitates creation, rather than a field or a practice. At the most fundamental level, the purpose of design is to develop an optimal solution for a given problem.</p> <p>    •    Is design an expression of art?</p> <p>Looking at art as any manifestation of human creativity and design as a process that facilitates creativity, then it would be more appropriate to say that art is most likely to be an expression of design.</p> <p>    •    What are the boundaries of design?</p> <p>Design is a process that is versatile and can be applied to any project that requires creativity.</p> <p>    •    Does design imply the idea of products that are necessarily useful?</p> <p>Labeling something as useful or not can be tricky because perception is largely in the eye of the beholder. The concept of usefulness varies greatly between individuals and even context. Gauging the success of a product is best done in terms of how well it performs relative to its design intent.</p> <p>    •    Ought form to derive from the analysis of function?</p> <p>Function should always drive form, but successful design is dependent upon balance. Applying form to an object without regard to purpose leads to sub-optimal solutions, as does the single-minded pursuit of function without consideration of aesthetics. Identifying the required function at the start of the design process gives purpose and intent to every stylistic decision made on the way to solving a problem. The resulting solution will strike the required balance between form and function.</p> <p>    •    Is design used to modify an old object through new techniques?</p> <p>Design methodologies revolve around the identification of a set of goals and iterating to an optimal solution. That can be applied to the creation or modification of an existing object for a given purpose.</p> <p>    •    Does design obey laws?</p> <p>In a way, design in itself is a set of laws, a sort of flexible framework for creative problem solving. That framework is essentially a method of breaking up large, complex problems to their most granular components. Those elements are then fed into a series of feedback loops, identifying and understanding constraints then iterating toward a solution. Breaking a complex problem down into a smaller pieces with well-defined goals leads to better solutions being developed.</p> <p>    •    Is design ephemeral?</p> <p>No, successful design will always stand the test of time despite stylistic elements. A purposeful and thoughtful solution that fulfills its design intent will overcome the ebb and flow of fads in the market. Products that bow to the temptation of the latest styling trends to justify their creation are essentially putting form ahead of function.</p> <p>    •    What do you feel is the primary condition for the practice of design and for its propagation?</p> <p>Counterintuitively, the most important element in a successful design process is well-established constraints. Creativity, and by extension design, doesn’t happen in a vacuum; it depends on outside inputs to work. The greater the variety and quality of inputs, the more potential there is for an optimal result. However, these inputs have to be balanced by constraints or it is impossible to identify the right solutions. This is doubly true for design processes that involve groups of people. Everyone needs to clearly understand the constraints. The limitations of the medium truly define the art.</p> <p>    •    What is the future of design?</p> <p>An individual today has access to a historically unprecedented volume of information and variety of tools from around the world. This knowledge base and the tools to manifest ideas are the fuel for creativity, but we are still limited by the mind’s ability to parse and store information. There is explosive potential when using technologies such as machine learning and artificial intelligence to augment human intellect in the design process.</p> <p>Notes - Design is a recursive process by which a solution is developed for a problem set within a given context through the holistic consideration of all factors affecting or being affected by that solution.</p> </div> </div>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Jonathan Wilson ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 15:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ gadgets ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ consumer technology ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ apple ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/review-henge-docks-gravitas-iphone-7-ipad-lightning-dock/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Scale of cyber attacks makes UK consumers more wary of new technology
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/scale-of-cyber-attacks-makes-uk-consumers-more-wary-of-new-technology/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3306/2017-04-05t150428z_1915389533_rc171ff335d0_rtrmadp_3_france-cyber.jpg?center=0.24102564102564103,0.453125&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131382806190000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3306/2017-04-05t150428z_1915389533_rc171ff335d0_rtrmadp_3_france-cyber.jpg?center=0.24102564102564103,0.453125&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131382806190000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The results of the survey, released as authorities continue to investigate the Petya-type malware strike, suggests that consumer confidence has been harmed by the attacks. Meanwhile, Nato has warned that cyber attacks could prompt a military response in future.</p> <p>The survey by software specialist SQS indicated 48 per cent of UK consumers would not buy new AI-driven products like Amazon Echo and Google Home because of fears they would be hacked. According to the survey, nearly 60 per cent of those asked said they feared autonomous vehicles would be vulnerable to cyber criminals and only a small minority thought driverless cars would be safer than human-driven vehicles.</p> <p><span>SQS chief executive Dik Vos said more focus should be placed on technology security to help ease concerns.</span></p> <p><span>He said: “Safety concerns and<span class="highlight"> cyber</span><span> vulnerabilities should be the top priority for companies developing innovative technology, rather than added as an afterthought or worse, once catastrophe has already struck.”</span></span></p> <p>The results of the survey of 2,000 people were released as the global scale of the most recent major computer virus attack continued to reveal itself.</p> <p>Huge international organisations like Danish shipping firm Maersk, French manufacturer Saint-Gobain and the German postal service were among those hit. Ukraine’s national bank and the Metro system in the capital, Kiev, were among the institutions in the ex-Soviet eastern European state which suffered significant disruption.</p> <p><span>Nato’s </span>Secretary-General Jens Stoltenberg<span> </span>has told journalists that future cyber attacks could potentially lead to the triggering of a clause in the military alliance’s treaty stating an attack on one of its members is viewed as an attack on all – an announcement that marks a ramping up of the rhetoric around cybercrime.</p> <p><span>A recent issue of </span><em>Nato Review Magazine</em> refers to the growing importance of cyber warfare in the “new Great Game” – a reference to proxy conflicts between Britain and Russia in the 1800s. There has long been concern in the Baltic states and other European Union countries close to the Russian border that the Kremlin could engage in a <span>“</span>hybrid<span>” conflict in which digital attacks would form a key part.</span></p> <p><span>It is not known who was behind the latest unleashing of malware said to resemble “Petya”, a piece of malicious code which bars access to computer by encrypting its hard drive. Kremlin spokesman Dmitry Peskov has denied his country was involved. However, the fact that Ukraine was by far the worst hit of all those countries affected means suspicion has fallen on Russia. </span></p> <p><span>The National Strategic Assessment, an annual public analysis of the nature and scale of organised crime compiled by the National Crime Agency, revealed that the primary threat to the UK from<span> <span>cyber</span></span><span> crime continued to stem from Russian-speaking nations. However, it also added that there were indications that the threat was becoming increasingly global.</span></span></p> <p>Arne Schoenbohm from the German government’s cybersecurity department said initial indications pointed to use in the latest string of attacks of malware which exploits the same weaknesses used in the WannaCry ransomware attack, the cyber assault that caused havoc in Britain’s National Health Service last month.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Josh Loeb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 15:16:10 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ security ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ cybersecurity ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ cyber-security ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/scale-of-cyber-attacks-makes-uk-consumers-more-wary-of-new-technology/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Two-armed construction robot clears disaster area debris with ease
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/two-armed-construction-robot-clears-disaster-area-debris-with-ease/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3861/dreamstime_xxl_60512487.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131432105860000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3861/dreamstime_xxl_60512487.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131432105860000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>In disaster areas, operating heavy construction equipment remotely and autonomously is necessary, but conventional remote-controlled heavy equipment often faces significant problems that are difficult to overcome.</p> <p>They can be too large and cumbersome to deal with in many disaster scenarios, can have limited mobility on slopes and stairs and imprecise remote controls lower their efficiency when clearing debris.</p> <p>The group of researchers from a number of Japanese universities have developed a prototype robot with a double-swing, dual-arm mechanism and hydraulic-powered robotic hands to overcome these issues.</p> <figure class="article-image"> <picture> <source media="(min-width: 1200px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3862/figure-1.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&rnd=131432105690000000"> <source media="(min-width: 960px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3862/figure-1.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432105690000000"> <source media="(min-width 760px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3862/figure-1.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=640&rnd=131432105690000000"> <source media="(min-width 320px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3862/figure-1.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=320&rnd=131432105690000000"> <!-- fallback image for non supporting browsers --> <img class="img-responsive lazyload" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==" data-src="/media/3862/figure-1.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432105690000000" /> </picture> <figcaption class="figure-caption fade-background"> <p class="image-caption">The prototype two-armed robot</p> </figcaption> </figure> <p>It is capable of handling heavy objects while excavating and gripping with its high-powered hands, as well as being able to adapt to different terrain types.</p> <p>Its double-swing, dual-arm mechanism is placed on the same axis, allowing it to use bearings with a far bigger diameter on its rotation portion in comparison to humans and animals, whose shoulder joints are arranged on different axes.</p> <p>The arms are positioned close to the robot’s centre of gravity, giving it a high degree of stability. This structure allows the robot to withstand high loads and perform heavy-duty work.</p> <p>Additionally, since each coaxially-arranged arm rotates at 360 degrees, there is no distinction between right and left arms, allowing the operator to freely change the layout of the robot’s hands.</p> <figure class="article-image"> <picture> <source media="(min-width: 1200px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3864/figure-3.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&rnd=131432105710000000"> <source media="(min-width: 960px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3864/figure-3.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432105710000000"> <source media="(min-width 760px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3864/figure-3.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=640&rnd=131432105710000000"> <source media="(min-width 320px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3864/figure-3.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=320&rnd=131432105710000000"> <!-- fallback image for non supporting browsers --> <img class="img-responsive lazyload" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==" data-src="/media/3864/figure-3.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432105710000000" /> </picture> </figure> <p>This group also developed a four-fingered hand that has been attached to one of the robot’s arms. The operating modes - excavation and grip - can be selected by changing the hand’s shape.</p> <p>It is also possible to change the hand depending on the shape of objects that it needs to interact with while also allowing for a wide range of grip strength.</p> <p>This robot has the capability to allow a remote operator to precisely control it by sensing the level of force and touch that it is applying to debris as if they were actually touching the target object.</p> <p>It is equipped with a multi-rotor unmanned aircraft vehicle UAV (a drone) which is powered through electric lines. This allows the operator to view objects and terrain from different viewpoints without a robot-mounted camera and gives it a bird’s-eye view which makes precise tasks and movement over intricate terrain easy.</p> <figure class="article-image"> <picture> <source media="(min-width: 1200px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3863/figure-2.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=1200&rnd=131432105700000000"> <source media="(min-width: 960px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3863/figure-2.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432105700000000"> <source media="(min-width 760px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3863/figure-2.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=640&rnd=131432105700000000"> <source media="(min-width 320px)" data-srcset="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3863/figure-2.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=320&rnd=131432105700000000"> <!-- fallback image for non supporting browsers --> <img class="img-responsive lazyload" src="data:image/gif;base64,R0lGODlhAQABAAAAACH5BAEKAAEALAAAAAABAAEAAAICTAEAOw==" data-src="/media/3863/figure-2.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&rnd=131432105700000000" /> </picture> </figure> <p>The researchers believe that these functions will dramatically increase construction equipment’s capacity to deal with large-scale disasters and accidents and say it could also replace conventional construction equipment used in civil engineering and construction projects.</p> <p>The robot could be used in disaster-relief situations within a few years after further improvements are made and its performance limits are tested.</p> <p>Last year, a team <a href="/content/articles/2016/02/disgusting-cockroach-robots-designed-to-locate-disaster-victims/" target="_blank">unveiled a miniature robot </a>that can squeeze itself into tiny gaps like a cockroach in order to search for disaster victims trapped in unreachable areas. </p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Jack Loughran ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 12:51:24 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ construction industry ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ disasters ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ robots ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/two-armed-construction-robot-clears-disaster-area-debris-with-ease/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
Israeli spy agency to offer equity-free grants in emerging technologies
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/israeli-spy-agency-to-offer-equity-free-grants-in-emerging-technologies/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3860/israeli-flags.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131432095200000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3860/israeli-flags.jpg?crop=0,0.256949482315336,0,0.25032068654019873&cropmode=percentage&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131432095200000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The Mossad, Israel’s intelligence agency, has set up a new fund to invest in emerging technologies to accelerate its technological capabilities.</p> <p>The technological innovation fund, the Libertad, will offer grants of up to two million shekels (£442,000) per project in exchange for rights to the technology. It will fund up to five projects a year. At the end of product development, the intelligence agency will receive a non-exclusive license for the know-how.</p> <p>According to the Mossad, the original developers would retain the rights to the products, and later be able to sell it on.</p> <p>“The Mossad wants to encourage innovation and creation of ground breaking technology […] the technology developed will be implemented by us, in cooperation between the parties,” a Libertad document explained.</p> <p>An Israeli government spokesperson said that Libertad would enable the Mossad to take advantage of Israel’s start-up ecosystem. The idea, he said, was not to buy into technology that already exists, but to be involved from the early stages of development.</p> <p>A government statement this week confirmed that Mossad would seek technologies in various fields relating to intelligence, including high-speed encryption, online personality profiling, miniaturised systems, biomimetics, all-terrain robotic capabilities, automated methods to collecting information from documents, and new approaches to stealth.</p> <p>The Mossad advised potential grant applicants to “closely observe” these areas of interest, and said that they would open public calls for proposals shortly. The statement that “anyone” can apply for funding suggests that the grants could be open to foreign start-ups, although only incorporated companies would be able to receive funding.</p> <p>Israel has over 450 registered cybersecurity companies. According to the Israel Venture Capital Research Centre, 78 start-ups raised more than 2.3 billion shekels (£510 million) from investors in 2016.</p> <p>Benjamin Betanyahu, the Israeli Prime Minister, posted a video on Twitter demonstrating futuristic espionage technology, captioned in Hebrew: “Mossad will continue to be sophisticated, daring and ground-breaking in its paramount task of ensuring Israel’s security.”</p> <div class="responsive-media video"> <blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-lang="en"><p lang="iw" dir="rtl">המוסד ימשיך להיות מתוחכם, נועז ופורץ דרך במשימתו העליונה להבטחת ביטחון ישראל. <a href="https://t.co/IN5x9xnrz7">pic.twitter.com/IN5x9xnrz7</a></p>&mdash; Benjamin Netanyahu (@netanyahu) <a href="https://twitter.com/netanyahu/status/879731687520960512">June 27, 2017</a></blockquote> <script async src="//platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script> </div> <p>In 1999, the US Central Intelligence Agency established In-Q-Tel (IQT), the non-profit “strategic investor” for accelerating emerging intelligence and defence technologies and delivering them to US intelligence organisations.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Hilary Lamb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 12:33:56 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ defence industry ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ government policies ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/israeli-spy-agency-to-offer-equity-free-grants-in-emerging-technologies/
</guid>
</item>
<item>
<title>
<![CDATA[
EDF charged with replacing Flamanville 3 nuclear reactor cover by 2024
]]>
</title>
<link>
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/edf-charged-with-replacing-flamanville-3-nuclear-reactor-cover-by-2024/
</link>
<media:content url="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3859/flamanville-construction.jpg?anchor=center&mode=crop&width=800&height=600&rnd=131432071020000000" medium="image"/>
<description>
<![CDATA[
<img src="https://eandt.theiet.org/media/3859/flamanville-construction.jpg?crop=0,0.39996388888888884,0,0.1073798611111112&cropmode=percentage&width=1200&height=450&rnd=131432071020000000" /><br /><br />
]]>
<![CDATA[
<p>The Flamanville 3 nuclear reactor, which is currently under construction in Northwest France, is expected to start up in 2018, although the project has suffered from delays, safety issues and overrun costs.</p> <p>One of the major safety issues raised regarded the irregularity of the steel of the
]]>
<![CDATA[
reactor cover and base. In 2014, carbon concentrations were discovered in the Areva-manufactured components and the ASN ordered EDF and Areva to carry out tests on the steel.</p> <p>After reviewing the findings, the ASN have provisionally ruled that the reactor is fit for service and the reactor base can operate safely over its projected 60-year lifetime. However, unless EDF can device new tests to prove the reliability of the steel, it must replace the faulty reactor cover by 2024.</p> <p>“The ASN considers that there are sufficient safety margins in order to start up the reactor,” stated Pierre-Franck Chevet, director of the ASN.</p> <p>Laurent Thieffry, who is leading EDF’s Flamanville 3 project, said that the company would comply with the ruling and attempt to devise new tests within two years. EDF will substitute the flawed reactor cover with a replacement which will be forged by Japan Steel Works, rather than Areva. This will take up to nine months and cost approximately €100 million.</p> <p>Greenpeace called on Nicolas Hulot, the French energy and environment minister, to halt the construction. “The ASN is no longer able to decide on safety in all independence and cannot resist industry pressure, simply because the survival of the entire French nuclear industry is at stake with the approval of this reactor vessel,” the pressure group argued.</p> <p>According to M. Chevet, the problems with the consistency of the steel could impact other European Pressurised Reactor (EPR) projects, including two currently under construction in Taishan, China, with bases and covers also manufactured by Areva’s Creusot Forge.</p> <p>An EPR under construction in Finland will be unaffected, as its components have been forged in Japan.</p> <p>The proposed Hinkley Point C nuclear power station in Somerset will contain two Areva-designed EPR reactors generating 3.2GW. The plant will have an estimated lifetime of 60 years, and will be mostly paid for by EDF and China General Nuclear Power Group.</p> <p>A final ruling is expected in October following a public consultation.</p> <p>If the regulator had ruled that the flawed steel would prevent a start-up of the reactor, entirely repairing the vessel would cost billions of euros. The regulator’s green light is a precondition for European Commission approval of EDF’s planned majority acquisition of Areva.</p>
]]>
</description>
<dc:creator>
<![CDATA[ Hilary Lamb ]]>
</dc:creator>
<pubDate>Thu, 29 Jun 2017 11:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
<category>
<![CDATA[ nuclear power ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ nuclear safety ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ legislation and regulation ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ steel ]]>
</category>
<category>
<![CDATA[ nuclear ]]>
</category>
<guid ispermalink="true">
https://eandt.theiet.org/content/articles/2017/06/edf-charged-with-replacing-flamanville-3-nuclear-reactor-cover-by-2024/
</guid>
</item>
</channel>
</rss>
